SSK字幕組
字幕由SSK字幕組傾情譯制
僅供學習，勿用於商，轉載請註明出處，版權歸片方所有
官網：www.sskzmz.com
更多內容可以關注我們的新浪微博
根據真實故事改編
馬塞諸塞州 波士頓 1976年
波 士 頓 警 察 局
十 一 區
怎樣了
How's that going?
那個媽媽在痛哭 那個舅舅氣得跳腳
The mother's bawling and the uncle's pissed off.
-她沒有結婚嗎 -離婚了 帶著四個孩子
- She's not married? - Divorced with four kids.
我猜 之前都是神父在幫忙
I guess father was helping out.
這也算幫忙
Helping out?
嘿 伯克先生 他們在後面和主教談話
Hey, Mr. Burke, they're in back talking to the bishop.
-神父呢 -我們讓他待在休息室
- And father? - We put him in the break room.
-有媒體來嗎 -有個《公民報》的記者 但我們打發他走了
- Any press? - Some guy from the citizen, but we sent him away.
-暫時還沒大報的人來 -繼續保持
- None of the big papers. - Let's keep it that way.
-那是誰 -助理地方檢察官
- Who's that? - Assistant da.
傳訊的時候就很難擋住那些媒體了
It's gonna be hard to keep the papers away from the arraignment.
哪會有什麼傳訊
What arraignment?
你告訴吉歐根神父我很快就好
You can tell father Geoghan I won't be much longer.
你看 希拉
Now, Sheila, you know
你知道教會在這個社區做了多少善事
what good work the church does in the community.
我以個人名義擔保
I give you my personal guarantee
我會讓神父離開這個教區
that I'm going to take father out of the parish
這種事不會再有第二次
and this will never happen again.
-我們還需要一會兒 保羅 -好的 神父
- We'll just be another moment, Paul. - Of course, father.
希拉 現在我以個人名義保證
Now, Sheila, I'm going to give you my personal guaran...
聚 焦
失去一位好記者的感覺總是不好受
Losing a good reporter is always tough.
《波士頓環球報》辦公樓  2001年7月
但失去一位精英中的精英
But losing one of our best--
額 我盡可能準確地描述
uh, well, to put it as eloquently as I can,
那感覺真的十分蛋疼
it's a real kick in the ass.
但羅比和斯圖爾特的
But Robby here has known
交情比你們大多數人活得還要久
Stewart longer than most of you have been alive,
所以接下來就讓他來說說吧
so I'll hand it off to him.
-羅比 -噢 謝謝 本
- Robby. - Oh, well, thanks, Ben.
其實不想謝你
I think.
儘管對你所說的我的資歷輩分 我並不盡認同
Although I take issue with your reference to my seniority,
但不可否認 斯圖爾特的離開對我來說特別痛苦
I will say that Stewart's departure is especially painful for me.
因為 斯圖爾特
Because for-- what, Stewart?
有二十年了吧
Twenty years now?
斯圖爾特一直
Stewart's been more than
勤勤懇懇地把錢輸在撲克桌上
willing to part with his money at the poker table.
而我還有個大學生要養
And I've got a kid in college.
-嗯 但我還會繼續玩的 -噢 那問題解決了
- Yeah, but I'm gonna keep playing. - Oh, problem solved.
那就祝你一切順利了
Godspeed then.
斯圖爾特 我覺得
Now, Stewart, I find the timing
你離開的時間特別煩人
of your departure disconcerting.
角落的辦公室空了
The corner office sits empty.
新編輯週一才到
The new editor arrives on Monday.
所以抱歉 兄弟 但我得問你
So I'm sorry, buddy, but I gotta ask ya,
你到底是怎麼辦事的
what the hell do you know?
蛋糕怎麼樣
How's the cake?
很好吃啊
It's really good.
-你留著不吃嗎 -不 這是給麥克的
- Are you saving yours? - Nah, it's for Mike.
-我吃不了這些東西 吃了我情緒不好 -我知道
- I can never eat at those things. They kind of depress me. - I know.
-你看到華盛頓的數據了嗎 -看了 很有意思
- Did you see the numbers from Washington? - Yeah. Very interesting.
我也覺得
I think so too.
我不是在問你警察局是不是在撒謊 我知道他們在撒謊
I'm not asking if the pd's lying. I know they're lying.
我要問的就是 這背後是誰在指使
All I'm asking-- who's behind it?
嗯哼 行 我知道了 你不想談
Uh-huh. Okay, I get it. You don't want to talk.
不 丹 我不是生氣 我是餓了
No, Dan. I'm not mad, I'm hungry.
我講了那麼久 還沒吃午飯呢
I've been talking so long I didn't eat lunch.
所以我要去找點吃的了
So I'm going to get something to eat.
正好給你一小時決定
That'll give you an hour to decide
你到底要不要在站在正確的一方
whether you want to be on the right side of this
還是想像其他人一樣讀著我們的報道
or read about it like everybody else.
-再見 丹 -你覺得卡希爾手上有料嗎
- Bye, Dan. - You think Cahill has something?
可能吧 我只是覺得我們不該做這個故事
Maybe. I just don't think the story's for us.
-本喜歡 -是啊 它還行
- Ben likes it. - Yeah, it's not bad.
-隻是不符合聚焦的風格 -什麼不符合
- It's just not spotlight. - What's just not spotlight?
-警察局的數據 -那個數據的報道 感覺很站不住腳
- The pd numbers. - The numbers story. It feels thin.
噢 你讓卡希爾開口了嗎
Oh. You got Cahill to talk?
還沒 但我會的
No. But I will.
很好 到時我們就知道站不站得住腳了
Good. Then we'll know if it's thin.
-樓上情況怎麼樣 -還不錯
- How'd it go upstairs? - Okay.
-羅比發表了一場很讚的演講 -毫無疑問
- Robby gave a good speech. - I'm sure he did.
我聽說魯賓和康奈爾
I heard Lubin and Connor
-要去《紐約時報》工作 -不是吧 真的嗎
- are going to the Times. - Come on. Really?
他們在吸我們的血
They're leeching us.
他們從邁阿密派了個人過來 情況應該會好點
They're sending a guy from Miami to run things. That should help.
巴倫之前在波士頓待過嗎
Has Baron even spent time in Boston?
我想他之前從沒來過這裏 我們應該給他買張地圖
I don't think he's been here before. We should buy him a map.
-我在邁阿密的一個朋友說他裁了百分之十五的員工 -真棒
- A friend down in Miami said he cut 15% of the staff. - Great.
嘿 羅比 新上司過來裁員的嗎
Hey, Robby. New boss coming in to make some cuts?
我不知道
I have no idea.
-你不是要和他坐下來談嗎 -是的
- Aren't you sitting down with him? - Yes, I am.
-是關於我們聚焦專欄嗎 -我不知道 麥克
- So is it about spotlight? - I don't know, Mike.
但我知道本想要
But I do know that Ben
那個犯罪數據的報道
needs an answer on the crime numbers story.
我和你說 我真的覺得我們不該做這個故事
I'm telling you, I really don't think that story's for us.
-巴倫先生 -噢
- Mr. Baron. - Oh.
沃爾特·羅賓森 叫我羅比就行
Walter Robinson. Robby. Yeah.
-感謝你週末抽空與我見面 -十分樂意
- Thanks for taking the time out of your weekend. - My pleasure.
-謝謝 -不客氣
- Appreciate it. - Pleasure.
-你在讀什麼 -額 《貝比魯斯魔咒》
- What are you reading? - Uh, curse of the bambino.
啊 那是本好書
Ah, yeah. It's a great book.
對了 你安頓下來後
The globe has season tickets
《環球報》會有芬威球場的季票
at Fenway once you're settled in, by the way.
謝謝 其實 我不是很喜歡棒球
Thank you. To be honest, I'm-- I'm not much of a baseball fan.
我只是試著感受這個城市的氛圍
I'm just trying to get a feel for the city.
噢 好吧
Oh. Yeah.
所以你是波士頓本地人嗎
So you're originally from Boston?
是的 土生土長
I am. Born and raised, yeah.
新聞編輯部裏很多人都是
A lot of the newsroom is from here.
感覺就好像是 一家本地報社
It really feels like a-- like a local paper in that way.
報紙被《紐約時報》收購後有改變這個感覺嗎
And did that change at all after the paper was sold to the times?
沒有 沒 我覺得還不至於有這麼大影響
No. No, I don't think that had a big impact.
很好
Good.
那麼 額 你是聚焦小組的編輯
And, uh, you're an editor for the spotlight team?
我更傾向於把自己當做是一個球隊教練 但 是的
I'd prefer to think of myself as player coach, but yes.
你熟悉聚焦嗎
Are you familiar with spotlight?
不是很瞭解
No, not particularly.
好吧 我們是由四個人組成的調查小組
Well, we are a four-person investigative team.
我們隸屬於本·布萊德利二世
We report to Ben bradlee Jr.,
我們工作保持絕對機密
and we keep our work confidential.
你們現在在跟進什麼
What are you working on now?
我們剛完結一個假冒建築公司的報道
We just put out a piece on a shoddy construction outfit,
現在我們只是在
and right now we're really
尋找有沒有值得挖掘的故事
just trolling around for our next story.
這一般需要多長時間
How long does that typically take?
很難說 額 幾個月吧
Hard to say. Uh, a couple months.
-幾個月 -是的
- Couple months? - Yeah.
我們不想操之過急
We don't like to rush it.
我們一旦選定一個項目
Once we settle on a project,
我們會花上一年甚至更多的時間去調查
we can spend a year or more investigating it.
-有什麼問題嗎 -不一定
- Is that a concern? - Not necessarily.
嗯 但從我所瞭解的看來 閱讀量正在下降
Um, but from what I understand, readership is down.
互聯網侵入了各行各業 還有 額
Internet is cutting into the classified business and, uh,
我想我需要對這些事情嚴肅對待
I think I'm gonna need to take a hard look at things.
所以 你希望精簡人員
So, you anticipate more cuts.
額 可以這麼說
Uh, I think it's safe to assume so.
但是 額 我現在更關注的是 要如何讓讀者
But, uh, what I'm more focused on right now is finding a way to--
覺得這份報紙不可或缺
to make this paper essential to its readers.
我覺得它已經做到了
I like to think it already is.
好吧 我只是認為我們可以做得更好
Fair enough. I just think that we can do better.
-布萊德利先生 -嘿
- Mr. Bradlee. - Hey.
看到警察局的數據了 看起來很有趣
Saw the pd numbers. Looks interesting.
是啊 裏面有點故事
Yeah, there's something there.
-你還需要多長時間 -額 再多一周
- How long do you need? - Uh, another week.
-你要去哪 -去開會啊
- Where are you going? - To the 10:30.
你什麼時候也要開會了
Since when?
嚴格來說 我是個編輯
Well, technically, I am an editor.
嚴格來說而已 你和巴倫聊的怎麼樣
Technically. Your sit-down with baron go that well?
-我讀不懂他這個人 -居然有你讀不懂的人
- I couldn't get a read on him. - That's a first.
-那你呢 -他是個開心果啊
- How about you? - Well, he's a barrel of laughs.
-大家早上好 -那我們開始吧
- Morning, everyone. - Let's get started.
你想說幾句嗎 馬蒂
Do you want to say something, Marty?
額 好的
Uh, sure.
額 大家好
Uh, hello.
額 大家應該都知道
Uh, as most of you know by now,
我叫馬蒂·巴倫
my name is Marty baron.
我 很開心來到這裏
I'm, uh, delighted to be here.
我們輪著說話的時候
Um, if you could tell me
如果你們能順便說一下自己的名字就更好了
your name as we go around, that'd be helpful.
謝謝
Thank you.
好的 彼得
Okay. Peter?
彼得·卡內洛斯 來自《都市報》
Peter canellos, Metro.
我有個大故事要挖完了
I've got a major big dig closure.
-嘿 史蒂夫 -麥克
- Hey, Steve. - Mike.
嘿 昨晚的比賽很爛吧
Hey. Crappy game last night, huh?
是啊 他們的擊球爛到爆了
Yeah, they can't hit worth a nickel.
嘿 聽著 那個
Hey, listen, what's,
艾琳·麥克納馬拉在會議室裏做什麼
um-- what's Eileen McNamara doing in the 10:30?
-你需要點什麼嗎 麥克 -不 我只是好奇
- Do you need something, Mike? - No, just curious.
去別的地方好奇去 我還有事要做呢
Go be curious somewhere else. I got work to do.
-好吧 史蒂夫 再見了 -不送
- Okay, Steve. See ya. - Yeah.
看來佩德羅要到九月一號才會重回賽場
And it looks like Pedro's gonna be out till September 1.
吉米說他今年就會重新開始比賽
Jimmy says he'll be back this year,
但醫生看起來沒那麼肯定
but the doc didn't seem so sure.
新英格蘭愛國者隊的開幕賽是什麼時候
When's the Pats opener?
大家都說過了嗎
Is that, uh, everyone?
-是的 -好的 謝謝
- Yes, that's it. - Okay. Good. Thank you.
大家讀過艾琳·麥克納馬拉這周的專欄了嗎
Uh, did everyone read Eileen McNamara's column this weekend?
是那個吉歐根的案子嗎
That's the geoghan case?
是的 後續報道如何
Yeah. What's the folo on that?
那就是個專欄 你想要怎麼樣的後續報道
It-- it's a column. What kind of folo were you thinking?
額 很顯然 三十年來 這位神父
Uh, well, apparently this priest molested kids
在六個不同教區都猥褻過兒童
in six different parishes over the last 30 years,
而受害者的律師 額
and the attorney for the victims, Mr., uh--
-加拉貝迪安先生 -謝謝 艾琳
- Garabedian. - Thanks, Eileen.
加拉貝迪安先生說勞紅衣主教
Mr. Garabedian says cardinal Law
十五年前就發現了他的行徑 卻無所作為
found out about it 15 years ago and did nothing.
我覺得那個律師是個怪人
I think that attorney's a bit of a crank.
教會也否認了這一說法
And the church dismissed the claim.
公說公有理 婆說婆有理
He said, she said.
不管加拉貝迪安先生是不是怪人
Whether Mr. Garabedian is a crank or not,
他說他有文件可以證明主教知道此事
he says he has documents that prove the cardinal knew.
據我所知 這些文件是密封的
As I understand it, those documents are under seal.
好吧 但事實就是事實 波士頓一位神父虐待八十位兒童
Okay, but the fact remains, a Boston priest abused 80 kids,
我們有一位律師聲稱可以證明勞知道此事
we have a lawyer who says he can prove Law knew about it,
而我們過去六個月裏也就寫了 兩篇報道
and we've written all of, uh, two stories in the last six months.
我認為這個故事對於一個本地報紙來說十分重要
This strikes me as an essential story to a local paper.
我想我們至少要瀏覽一遍那些文件
I think at the very least we have to go through those documents.
你想怎麼做呢
How would you like to do that?
額 我不清楚這裏的法律
Well, uh, I don't know what the laws are here,
但在佛羅里達 我們會上法庭
but in Florida, we would go to court.
你想要控告教會嗎
You want to sue the church?
嚴格來說 我們不會控告教會
Technically, we wouldn't sue the church.
我們只是提出動議 要求公開密封文件
We'd file a motion to lift the seal on those documents.
教會會理解為我們要控告他們
The church will read that as us suing them.
大家都會這麼認為
So will everybody else.
謝謝告知
Good to know.
-新官上任三把火啊 -這說得真沒錯
- Gutsy call for the first day. - That's one word for it.
你覺得這會有什麼後果
How do you think that's gonna play down front?
我想吉爾曼會很擔心
I think Gilman's gonna shit a brick.
-嘿 -關門
- Hey. - Door.
怎麼樣
How'd it go?
巴倫想要提出動議 公開吉歐根一案的密封文件
Well, Baron wants to sue for the sealed docs in the Geoghan case.
他想要控告教會嗎 嘿 那很好啊
He wants to sue the church? Hey, that's great. Yeah.
三年前事發之時 我們報道過吉歐根
We covered Geoghan when the story broke three years ago.
那時巴倫還在邁阿密
Baron was still in Miami.
-其實那時他可能在《時報》 -反正他不在這裏
- He might have been at the times then, actually. - He wasn't here.
所以你覺得這有希望嗎
So do you think that suit has a chance?
-要看法官了 -以及他屬於哪個教區
- Depends on the judge. - And what parish he belongs to.
布萊德利 嗯
Bradlee. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
-巴倫想和我們談談 -我們嗎
- Baron wants to talk to us. - Us?
-好的 喬 -謝謝
- Okay, Joe. - Thank you.
好的 謝謝
Yes. Okay, thanks.
我已經定了明天要和外部法律顧問見面
I've set up a meeting for tomorrow with outside counsel.
-喬·阿爾巴諾嗎 -是的
- Joe albano? - Yeah.
這個案子的法官是誰
Who's the judge in this case?
額
Um...
康斯坦絲·斯威尼
Constance Sweeney.
-難搞的人 -為什麼
- Tough. - Why's that?
天主教乖乖女
Good catholic girl. Huh.
所以 從我所讀到的來說
So, um, judging from what I've read,
看來我們並沒有
it doesn't seem like we've done a
十分徹底地調查過吉歐根的案子
very thorough investigation into the Geoghan case.
-是嗎 -並不是
- Is that right? - No, it's not.
我們很認真地調查過這案子
We looked hard at geoghan.
《都市報》的大衛·阿姆斯特朗 還有宗教記者邁克爾·保爾森
David Armstrong from Metro, Michael Paulson for religion.
好吧 但我瞭解到
Okay, but, uh, just so I understand,
除了我們的日常報道
beyond our daily coverage, we haven't--
我們還沒有對勞主教是否知情一事
we haven't committed any long-term investigative resources
展開過任何長期調查
to the question of whether or not cardinal Law knew about this.
是的 沒有
No, we haven't.
而這正是你們小組幹的事對嗎
And that's the kind of thing your team would do?
聚焦嗎 嗯 是啊
Spotlight? Well, yeah.
但我們還在調查我和你提過的那個波士頓警局的故事
But we're still prospecting the Boston pd story I told you about.
-你們可以先把那個放一放嗎 -可以
- Could you set that aside? - We could.
馬蒂 過去聚焦小組總能成功
Marty, in past spotlight's had success in large part
是因為他們自己挑選想調查的項目
because they pick their own projects.
那你們會考慮挑選這個嗎
Would you consider picking this one?
我不知道他是不是在寫你的事
I don't know if he's writing about you,
但我會告訴他你打過電話
but I will let him know you called.
-好的 拜拜 -嘿
- Okay. Bye. - Hey.
-嘿 怎麼樣了 -還行吧
- Hey, how'd it go? - Okay.
額 巴倫想我們去弄清楚吉歐根的案子
Uh, Baron wants us to scrub the Geoghan case.
-那很好啊 -我們不是報道過吉歐根嗎
- That's great. - Didn't we cover geoghan?
是啊 有個律師聲稱勞主教知情
Yeah, there's a lawyer alleging cardinal law knew about it.
-嗯 米奇·加拉貝迪安 是嗎 -是的
- Mmm. Mitch Garabedian, right? - Yeah.
-我在法院那報道過他 -你能聯繫到他嗎
- I covered him at the courthouse. - Can you get to him?
我只採訪過他一次 他還有點個性
I only interviewed him once. He's kind of a character.
-我就喜歡有個性的人 我來搞定他 -很好 你負責
- I like characters. I'll take him. - Good. You take him.
還有 我們要找波特一案中的
Also, we should be talking to the
受害者代表律師談談
lawyer who repped the victims in the Porter case.
-埃裏克·麥克利什 -那傢伙總上電視
- Eric Macleish. - That guy was always on TV.
-波特一案 和我說說 -嗯 額
- The Porter case? Remind me. Yeah, uh--
神父波特 相似的故事
father Porter, similar story.
十年前在福爾裏弗猥褻了許多兒童
Molested dozens of kids in Fall River about 10 years ago.
-所以我們要放棄波士頓警局的故事嗎 -我贊成
- So we're dropping the Boston pd? - I-I vote yes.
不 我們只是暫時將它放一邊
No. We just gotta set it aside for now.
不需要我和你們強調了
I don't need to tell you guys this.
我們這次要比平常更加謹慎
We need to be more discreet than usual.
所有人都會對這件事很感興趣 不僅僅是《先驅報》
Everybody's going to be interested in this, not just the Herald.
在我們掌握有用的信息之前
We can't let cardinal Law
不能讓勞主教知道半點風聲
get wind of this till we know what we have.
祝我們好運吧
Good luck with that.
你什麼時候走 奶奶
So when do you leave, Nana?
巴士九點會在教會的停車場接我們
The bus is picking us up in the church parking lot at 9:00.
我們有四十個人要去
We have 40 people going.
-多米尼克神父也去嗎 -不 他說他運氣不好
- And is father Dominic going? - No. He says he's unlucky.
但這和運氣沒什麼關係
But luck has nothing to do with it.
-你知道嗎 上次奶奶贏了一百六十刀 -哇噢
- You know, last time Nana won $160. - Wow.
你要告訴她嗎
You gonna tell her?
我們還不知道這其中到底有沒有料
We don't even know if there's a story yet.
《環球報》控告教會 這本身就是個猛料
Globe sues church? It's gonna be a story.
嘿 麗莎 能把所有相關的剪報都找給我嗎
Hey, Lisa. Could you pull all the relevant clips on that for me?
好的
Yeah.
是給聚焦的嗎
Is this for spotlight?
準備好了就拿過來吧 謝了
Just drop them off when they're ready. Thanks.
不好意思 你知道出版商的辦公室在哪嗎
Excuse me. Do you know where the publisher's office is?
好的
Will do.
你好啊 馬蒂
How are you, Marty?
還適應嗎
Settling in?
嗯 還行
Yeah, I think so.
很好 有什麼能為你效勞嗎
Good. What can I do for you?
嗯
Um...
我想對吉歐根一案的保護令提出反對
I'd like to challenge the protective order in the Geoghan case.
你想控告天主教會嗎
You want to sue the catholic church?
額
Um--
我們現在只是提出動議 不過 是的
we're just filing a motion, but, uh, yes.
你覺得真的有這個必要嗎
You think it's that important?
是的
Yes, I do.
因為教會肯定會十分激烈地反擊我們
Because obviously the church will fight us very hard on this.
我們的訂閱者也會注意到
Which won't go unnoticed by our subscriber base.
其中百分之五十三都是天主教徒
53% of them are catholic.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
我想他們會感興趣的
I think they'll be interested.
好吧
Okay.
馬蒂 教會的人可能會
Marty, lake street will probably
聯繫你與主教進行面談
contact you about a face-to-face with the cardinal.
-這是慣例 -嗯
- It's customary. - Yeah.
他們已經找我了 定在下周
They already have. It's set up for next week.
要是我 我就不會提起這件事
I wouldn't mention this.
有人嗎
Hello?
-有什麼能幫你的嗎 -噢 嗨 我是《波士頓環球報》的麥克·雷贊德斯
- Can I help you? - Oh, hi. I'm Mike Rezendes from the Boston Globe.
我是來見米切爾·加拉貝迪安的
I'm here to see Mitchell Garabedian.
他正在講電話 先請坐吧
He's on a call. Please have a seat.
好的
Okay.
好了 我在聽 繼續吧
All right, I'm listening. Go ahead.
好
Okay.
比爾 那些文件死哪去了
Bill! Where the hell are those papers?
我叫你放我桌子上的
I asked you to put 'em on my desk!
大名鼎鼎的沃爾特·羅賓森蒞臨我的會議室
The famous Walter Robinson in my conference room.
很高興再會 埃裏克 薩夏·法伊弗 埃裏克·麥克利什
Good to see you again, Eric. Sacha Pfeiffer, Eric macleish.
-很高興認識你 -很高興認識你 你不打高爾夫吧
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you. You don't play golf, do you?
-額 不打 -很好
- Uh, no. - Good.
你這位同事去年
Your colleague here took
在一個慈善活動上敲了我一把
some money off me at a charity event last year.
那一桿真是走運
It was a very lucky putt.
順便說一句 其實那時我還是閉著眼的
I actually had my eyes closed, by the way.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
所以有什麼可以幫你們的嗎
So how can I help you guys?
額 你瞭解吉歐根那個案子嗎
Uh, you're familiar with the geoghan case?
當然 八十個原告
Sure. Eighty plaintiffs.
都是獨立的個案
All of them individual cases.
加拉貝迪安都要忙暈了吧
Garabedian must be swimming.
是啊 所有指控都指向勞主教嗎
Yeah. And the allegations against cardinal Law?
是啊 挺棘手的
Yeah, it's tricky. Um--
你們要清楚這一點 這些案子都很麻煩
this is what you need to understand. These are shitty cases.
嗯 訴訟時效只有三年
Um, the statute of limitations is only three years,
而大部分受害者
and most of these victims
都要很多年後才來尋求法律的幫助
don't come forward till long after that.
-噢 為什麼 -你知道的 他們都是孩子
- Oh. Why is that? - Well, they're kids, you know.
愧疚感 羞恥感
Uh, guilt, shame.
大部分孩子都來自家教嚴厲的社區
And most of these kids come from tough neighborhoods.
沒人想要承認這種事的發生
Nobody wants to admit this kind of thing.
所以在訴訟時效上就已經沒轍了
So you're screwed on the time limit.
而且 額 就算給你說通了這一點
And, uh, even if you argue your way around that,
慈善豁免法令的賠償金就兩萬美元
the charitable immunity statute caps damages at 20 grand.
猥褻一個兒童才賠償兩萬美元
Twenty grand for molesting a child?
是的 這個系統就是這麼運轉的
That is the way the system is set up, yes.
教會不好對付
The church is tough.
所以最好的方法就是讓媒體報道這些案子
So your best shot is to try these cases in the press,
就好像在波特一案中我所做的那樣
uh, like I did on Porter.
-嗯 -但大多數受害者
- Mmm. - But you know, most of the victims,
他們都不想和電視媒體扯上關係
they don't want to have anything to do with TV.
還有就是 米奇不算是個好相處的人
And, uh, Mitch isn't exactly a people person.
嗯 而且如果加拉貝迪安
Yeah. And if garabedian
沒法說服他的受害者接受媒體的報道
can't get his victims to go before the press,
-那他就真的 -沒錯
- then he's really-- - Yeah, that's right.
他接下來的路很漫長啊
He has a long road ahead of him.
我的猜測是他並沒有抓到勞的把柄
My guess is he doesn't have anything on Law.
什麼 你覺得他只是在嚇唬他還是
What? You think he's bluffing or--
我覺得他是故意吹噓來達成更好的交易
I think he's grandstanding to cut a better deal.
看起來有點魯莽啊
Seems a bit reckless.
你們見過米奇·加拉貝迪安嗎
Have you met Mitch Garabedian?
我叫你起草那個動議 比爾
I asked you to write up that motion, Bill.
我沒叫你提交
I didn't ask you to file it!
他嗎
Mmm?
嘿 比爾
Hey, bill.
嗨
Hi.
-你是誰 -我是《波士頓環球報》的麥克·雷贊德斯
- Who are you? - I'm Mike rezendes from the Boston globe.
我預約了和你一小時前見面的
I had an appointment with you about an hour ago.
我沒法和你談 我很忙 莎倫
I can't talk to you. I'm very busy. Sharon?
她出去買咖啡了 她說她很快回來
She went out for coffee. She said she'd be right back.
我在追蹤採訪一篇文章
I'm following up on an article.
-《鳳凰報》那篇嗎 -不是 《環球報》那篇
- The one in the Phoenix? - No. In the globe.
-你讀了《鳳凰報》那篇嗎 -還沒有
- Did you see the one in the Phoenix? - No, I didn't.
我覺得寫得很好 我這好像有一份
I thought it was very good. I have a copy here somewhere.
沒事 我晚點再看
That's all right. I'll track it down.
其實我是在追蹤採訪
I'm actually following up on a
艾琳·麥克納馬拉專欄裏報道的關於你那一個訴訟的
column that Eileen McNamara wrote about your suit.
不是一個 有八十四個
Suits. There are 84 of them.
那不是一起集體訴訟 你要補補背景知識
It's not a class action. You should get your facts straight.
你說得對 我應該瞭解清楚
No, you're right. I should.
我現在只是想問一些背景信息
So I'm trying to get some background information on--
你沒在錄音吧
you're not recording this, are you?
沒有 我不會不經允許就錄音的
Uh, no. I wouldn't do that without asking.
我不能給你看教會的文件
I can't show you the church documents,
如果你想要的是這個的話
if that's what you're after.
-它們是密封的 -嗯 我知道
-They're under seal. -Yeah, I know that.
你知道他們三次試圖
Did you know they tried to bring me up
在馬塞諸塞州律師監督委員會那告發我嗎
before the Massachusetts board of bar overseers three times?
-他們盯我盯得很緊 -教會嗎
- They're watching me very closely. - The church?
是的 教會
Yeah. The church. Yeah.
他們想要取消我的律師資格
They'd like to get me disbarred.
事實上 拿開 把那拿開
In fact-- put that away. Put it away.
-沒問題 -我不想你記錄這段對話
- Sure. - I don't want you recording this
無論什麼形式都不行
in any way, shape or form.
筆錄 錄音 都不行
Not on paper, not on tape, nothing.
事實上 我可能甚至都不應該和你說話 所以
In fact, I probably shouldn't even be speaking to you, so--
聽著 加拉貝迪安先生 我知道你有東西不能告訴我
look, Mr. Garabedian, I know there's things you cannot tell me.
但我也知道這當中有個故事
But I also know there's a story here,
而我覺得這是個很重要的故事
and I think it's an important story.
我已經和《鳳凰報》談過了
I already talked to the Phoenix.
我知道 我沒讀那篇文章也是有原因的
Yeah, and there's a reason I didn't see it.
現在沒人看《鳳凰報》了
Nobody reads the Phoenix anymore.
它們破產了 它們沒什麼力量了
They're broke. They don't have any power.
但《環球報》有
The globe does.
如果我們報道這個故事 所有人都會知道
If we cover this story, everybody will hear about it.
教會的力量積攢了無數個世紀 雷贊德斯先生
The church thinks in centuries, Mr. Rezendes.
你覺得你們報紙有這個資源來擔當起這件事嗎
Do you think your paper has the resources to take that on?
是的 我相信
Yeah, I do.
只要你不介意我問你問題
But if you don't mind me asking, do you?
我現在沒空和你聊天 雷贊德斯先生
I can't talk to you right now, Mr. Rezendes.
我真的非常 非常忙
I'm very, very busy.
-莎倫 -謝謝你
- Sharon? - Thank you.
能至少讓我和你的一些客戶談一談嗎 那些受害者
Yep. Can I at least talk to some of your clients? The victims?
我真的想這麼做
I'd really like to do that.
-明天再給我打電話吧 我要考慮一下 -好的 謝謝你 十分感謝
- Call me tomorrow. I gotta think about it. - Yep. Thank you. Thanks.
艾琳·麥克納馬拉 著
相似的套路
主教伯納德·勞對此不予置評
神父約翰·J·吉歐根是嫌疑人
因1987年性侵索賠
波特站上馬塞諸塞州法庭
-我找到更多剪報了 -放那吧
- I got more clips from the library. - Leave 'em right there.
你們在做關於教會的報道嗎
Are you guys doing a story on the church?
不 我們沒在做關於教會的報道
No, we are not doing a story on the church.
馬特 你有找到這個人的資料嗎 菲爾·薩維亞諾
Matt, you find anything on this guy, Phil Saviano?
沒有 他是誰
No. Who is he?
他是受害者組織中的成員
He's part of a victims' organization.
波特一案後柯吉恩做過他的報道
Kurkjian did a story on him right after the Porter case.
-還有個受害者組織 -是啊
- There's a victims' organization? - Yeah.
叫作斯納普 這是
It's called snap. It's, uh,
遭神父虐待之苦的受害者群體的縮寫
survivors network of those abused by priests.
-真可憐的名字 -嗯
- Crummy acronym. - Mmm.
-要我查查他嗎 -嗯 好的
- You want me to track him down? - Yeah. Bring him in.
你還需要多長時間看完這些剪報
How much longer you need to get through the clips?
好幾天吧 有好多
I mean, a few days. There's a lot.
-麗莎還在源源不斷地送過來 -行
- Lisa's still sending up more. - Okay.
嘿 大伙 我好像又找到一位神父了
Hey, guys. I think I got another priest.
利亞姆·巴雷特
Liam Barrett.
波士頓
總教區
遭指控
神父
性虐待
在費城猥褻過一些孩子
Molested some kids in Philly
後來搬到了波士頓
and was moved to Boston.
故技重施 然後又搬走了
Did the same thing and was moved again.
真的嗎 聽起來和吉歐根的案子很像
Really? That sounds like geoghan.
-這是我們的剪報嗎 -是啊 署名是迪亞哥·日巴迪內亞 1997年
Is that one of our clips? Yeah. Byline's Diego ribadineira, 1997.
肯定是他在做宗教工作之時回來了
Must've been back when he was working religion.
-有後續報道嗎 -沒多少 只有一小篇
- Was there any folo? - Not much. One short piece.
嗯 教會私下解決了
Huh. The church settled the case.
你不是認識吉姆·蘇利文嗎
Don't you know Jim Sullivan?
是啊 怎麼了
Yeah. Why?
看來教會找他幫忙了
Looks like the church brought him in to help out.
老天 除了曼尼還有人把球打出內場嗎
Jesus. Has anybody but Manny gotten the ball out of the infield?
沒有 你怎麼在弄那個
Nope. Why do you even bother with that thing?
它能讓我不去看比賽
It distracts me from the game.
知道還有什麼東西能幫到你嗎
Know what else is good for that?
噢對 好主意 該我去了
Oh, yeah. Good idea. My round.
-很快回來 有人要吃的嗎 -沒有
- I'll be right back. Anybody want any food? - No.
-我都有了 -嘿 帶根熱狗
- I'm all set. - Hey, a hot dog.
-你們有什麼進展嗎 -當然有
- So, you guys making any progress? - Absolutely.
-那是個好故事 -為什麼這麼說
- It's a good story. - Why?
因為你也是一個被教會惹怒的叛教者嗎
'Cause you're another lapsed catholic pissed off at the church?
-我們找到了很多猛料 -比如說呢
- We've got a lot of good stuff. - Like what?
我只是在專心看比賽 什麼都聽不到
I'm just watching the game. Omerta?
他們找到另一位神父 利亞姆·巴雷特
They got another priest-- Liam Barrett.
我們報道過他 我只是這麼一說 我沒說錯呀
We reported on him. I'm just saying, we did.
好吧 但這個傢伙
Okay, but this guy was shuffled
每過幾年就換一個教區
around from parish to parish every few years,
就像吉歐根和波特一樣
just like geoghan and Porter.
我覺得這有模式可循
I think there's a pattern.
這推測站不住腳 你還發現了什麼
Sounds thin. What else you got?
薩夏從一個受害者組織裏
Sacha's got another guy
找到了一個叫菲爾·薩維亞諾的傢伙
from a victims' organization-- Phil saviano.
是斯納普組織裏的嗎 哦 天吶 我們也報道過他
From snap? Oh, boy. We reported on him too.
你不是在看球賽嗎 史蒂夫
I thought you were watching the game, Steve.
-那傢伙被傷得很重 -我們寫過幾篇他的報道
- That guy's pretty banged up. - We did a couple stories on him.
他一直堅持寫信
Guy would not stop writing letters.
-他想發起聖戰 -怎麼 難道問他沒什麼意義嗎
- He wants a holy war. - What, so he's not worth talking to?
-你對加拉貝迪安的調查怎麼樣了 -還在查呢
- Where are you on garabedian? - I'm working on it.
羅比說麥克利什認為他在虛張聲勢
Robby says macleish thinks he's bluffing.
本 我覺得這裏面有料可挖
I think there's something there, Ben.
給我點可靠的證據 不然你們就別幹了
Get me something solid, or I'm taking you off it.
我不想我們因為這件事瞎忙活
I don't want us chasing our tails on this.
不要撞到障礙物
Stay away from that trap!
你想打到那裏還早得很呢 夥計
You couldn't reach that trap in a million years, partner.
我以前就打中過
I've reached that trap before.
是麼 現在輪到保羅了
Yeah. Now, Paul, maybe.
-怎麼樣 -挺好的
- How we doing? - We're good.
-我們領先了兩分 -很好
- We're two up on the front. - Good.
新編輯怎麼樣
How's that new editor working out?
呃 他可不怎麼喜歡棒球
Well, he doesn't like baseball.
但是 額 他看上去挺聰明的
But, uh, he seems like a smart guy.
嗯 我看過一篇關於他的文章
Yeah, I read an article about him.
上面說他是《環球報》第一位猶太人編輯
Said he's the first Jewish editor of the globe.
真是信息閉塞啊
Must have been a slow news day.
-他結婚了嗎 -沒有
- He got a family, this guy? - No.
他還沒結婚
He is not married.
-是離婚了嗎 -我覺得不是
- Divorced? - I don't think so, no.
也就是說這位《環球報》的
So the new editor at the
新編輯是有著猶太信仰的未婚男人
globe is an unmarried man of the Jewish faith
還不喜歡棒球
who hates baseball?
-是啊 -這位子應該給本的
- Yeah. - Should have given it to Ben.
他可是布萊德利家的人
He's a bradlee, for crying out loud.
我想 也許是他手舉得還不夠快吧
Didn't raise his hand fast enough, I guess.
嘿 順便一提
Hey, by the way,
我最近在看那個巴雷特神父的資料
I've been reading about this priest, father Barrett.
上面說你參與過這個案子
Said you were involved with that.
巴雷特 哦 壞傢伙
Barrett, yeah. Bad egg.
當時教會來找我幫忙 我就參與了
Lake street asked for help. I pitched in.
受害者們說當勞主教
Victim said cardinal law
從費城過來的時候就知道巴雷特的事了
knew about Barrett when he came from Philly.
這是真的嗎
Is that true?
你知道我不能談論這個案子 羅比
You know I can't talk about the case, robby.
呃 私下也不行嗎
Well... off the record?
私底下也不行 我不能說
Off the record, I can't talk about it.
-好吧 -這和訴訟有關係嗎
- All right. - This related to the lawsuit?
你知道這回事
You know about that?
聽著
Look,
我不認識這個叫巴倫的人 也不知道他的計劃
I don't know this guy Baron or what his agenda is.
坦白說 我也不在乎
Frankly, I don't care.
我只是不想你替他擋子彈
I just don't want to see you taking a bullet for him.
我覺得你太過火了
I think you're away.
-放在這兒 -我們走 走
- Put it over here. - Let's go. Let's go.
某天我正在上網
So the other day I was on the world wide web.
你想知道的任何事 在網上都找得到
Anything you want to know, it's right there.
我不得不承認 身為一個神父
Now, I have to admit that as a priest,
這不免讓我感到有些緊張
this makes me a little nervous.
我該擔心自己的工作保障嗎
Should I be worried about job security?
我看不需要
I don't think so.
你看 知識是一回事
You see, knowledge is one thing.
但信仰就是另一回事了
But faith-- faith is another.
嘿
Hey.
你不是應該在高爾夫或者別的什麼嗎
Shouldn't you be golfing or something?
高爾夫可不是個動詞
Golfing's not a verb.
我也沒有開球時間啊
And I couldn't get a tee time.
人們都是這麼稱呼的嗎 開球時間
Is that what they call it? Tee time?
他們還稱它為休閒活動
They also call it a leisure activity.
-你該試試 麥克 -我試了 我去跑步了
- You oughta try it, Mike. - I do. I run.
沒錯 但你是跑步來上班
Yeah. You run to work.
那你今天在這兒做什麼
So why are you here today?
-在反覆看薩維亞諾的剪報 -好吧
- Going over these clips of saviano. - Yep.
本和史蒂夫認為這條路走不通
Ben and Steve think it's a dead end.
他們在看比賽時說了一堆廢話
They gave me a bunch of crap about it at the game.
嗯 本給我發了郵件
Yeah, Ben e-mailed me.
-是嗎 -嗯
- He did? - Yeah.
他說我們該放手了
He said we should let it go.
那你想怎麼做
What do you want to do?
我想去查一下薩維亞諾
I want to bring saviano in.
那你不管這些傢伙了嗎
So, just ignore those guys?
我想我們在這件事上不該理會任何人的話
I think we oughta start ignoring everybody on this one.
這我可以做到
I'm good with that.
那麼
Well--
你覺得馬蒂對這些有什麼看法嗎
do you think Marty has any idea what's coming down the pike?
沒有 我也覺得他不在乎
Nope. I don't think he cares either.
那可真新鮮
That's refreshing.
嗯
Yeah.
除非他錯了
Unless he's wrong.
我一直都很喜歡報刊業
I've always been fascinated with the newspaper business.
我在哈佛讀書的時候曾經也和
I used to sit in on the lectures
內曼兄弟一起上過這樣的課程
with the neiman fellows when I was at Harvard.
我 額 在文章上看到你曾經也是一個編輯
I, uh-- I read that you were an editor once.
啊 是的
Ah, yes.
嗯 那是很久以前的事了
Yeah, that was a very long time ago.
《密西西比報》
The Mississippi register.
主教管區的小報紙
Small diocesan newspaper.
但對一位三十歲的牧師來說 也是一份重大的責任啊
But for a 30-year-old pastor, it was a big responsibility.
有時過於沉重了
Too much at times.
怎麼說
How so?
我曾和埃弗斯兄弟關係不錯
I was close with the evers brothers.
我們在公民權利的問題上表明了立場
We took a stand on civil rights.
我們的讀者不開心了
Our readership was not pleased.
他們把我當成瞎插手的局外人
They saw me as a meddling outsider.
我能想像
I can imagine.
這位子可不好坐 尤其是在一個小鎮子
Tough seat to sit in, especially in a small town.
我想你會發現波士頓其實也是個小地方的 馬蒂
I think you'll find that Boston's still a small town too, Marty,
從很多方面看都是
in many ways.
嗯
Hmm.
但如果有任何地方我能幫得上忙的 馬蒂 儘管直說
But if I can be of any help, Marty, don't hesitate to ask.
我發現 當一個城市裏的各個機構都
I find that the city flourishes
齊心協力的時候 這個城市就能變得繁榮
when its great institutions work together.
謝謝你
Thank you.
就我個人觀點來看
Personally I'm of the opinion
一份報紙要能最好地發揮它的功能
that for a paper to best perform its function,
它就不能依靠外在的力量
it really needs to stand alone.
啊 當然了
Ah. Of course.
但我的提議仍然有效
But my offer still stands.
謝謝你
Thank you.
請進
Come in.
哦
Ah.
謝謝 莫林
Thank you, Maureen.
一份小禮物 馬蒂
A little gift, Marty.
把它當成是紅衣主教對波士頓的指引吧
Think of it as a cardinal's guide to the city of Boston.
教義問答書
我是來見薩夏·法伊弗的
I'm here to see sacha pfeiffer.
-你的名字是 -菲爾·薩維亞諾
- Your name? - Phil saviano.
-好 稍等片刻 -嗯
- Okay, just a minute. - Mm-hmm.
我是第一個跟你們交談的倖存者嗎
So, am I the first survivor you've talked to?
對的 菲爾 你是第一個
Yeah, Phil, you are.
好吧 那麼
Okay, well,
首先我要感謝你們今天邀請我來
first of all let me say thank you for having me in today.
其次 我想知道你們是否
And I want you to know that you
和我所屬的斯納普組織全權合作了
have the full cooperation of my organization, snap.
菲爾 你的組織裏有多少人
How many members are in your organization, Phil?
上次開會有十一人
We had 11 at our last chapter meeting--
呃 不 是十個 凱倫離開了
uh, no, um, 10. Karen just moved.
-你們團隊裏還有個女人 -當然了
- You had a woman in your group? - Of course.
他們不會區別對待的 施虐不分男女
They don't discriminate, not when it comes to abuse.
這和是不是同性戀也沒關係
And this has nothing to do with being gay.
這就是神父利用職權來強姦孩子
What this is is priests using the collar to rape kids.
都是孩子啊 有男有女
Kids. Boys and girls.
那時我十一歲
I was 11,
我被伍斯特市的大衛·霍利神父折磨
and I was preyed upon by father David holley in worcester.
註：英文中prey和pray發音相似
我不是說向他禱告 而是受他折磨
And I don't mean prayed for. I mean preyed upon.
-你們中有誰是天主教徒嗎 -我在信奉天主教的家庭裏長大
- Are any of you catholic? - I was raised catholic.
不過現在我去我妻子的基督教長老會
Now I go to my wife's presbyterian church.
我沒有信仰
I'm lapsed.
但我有時和奶奶一起去教堂
I go to church with my grandmother sometimes.
之前說我們都在信奉天主教的家庭長大是一件很光榮的事 但現在
It's safe to say we were all raised catholic, but now--
-沒這種感覺了 -好吧
- not so much. - Okay.
那麼 我告訴你們
Well, let me tell you,
如果你是一個出身貧寒的窮小子
when you're a poor kid from a poor family,
宗教就很重要了
religion counts for a lot.
而且若是神父能注意到你 那可是非同小可的大事
And when a priest pays attention to you, it's a big deal.
他會讓你收集讚美詩
He asks you to collect the
或者倒垃圾 你會覺得自己是特別的
hymnals or take out the trash, you feel special.
就像上帝讓你幫忙一樣
It's like god asking for help.
所以當他給你講黃段子的時候 你可能會覺得有點奇怪
So maybe it's a little weird when he tells you a dirty joke.
但你們有了共同的秘密 於是你選擇了順從
But now you got a secret together, so you go along.
然後他給你看色情雜誌 你也順從他
Then he shows you a porno mag, and you go along.
就這樣 你一直順從他 聽他的話
And you go along, and you go along,
直到某天他讓你為他打手槍或吹喇叭
until one day he asks you to jerk him off or give him a blow job.
你也會順從他 因為你覺得非做不可
And so you go along with that too because you feel trapped,
因為他一手栽培了你
because he has groomed you.
你怎麼能對上帝說不呢 對吧
How do you say no to god, right?
你們要理解
See, it is important to
這不僅僅是身體上的虐待
understand that this is not just physical abuse.
這也是精神上的虐待
It's spiritual abuse too.
當一個神父對你做了這些事 他搶劫了你的信仰
And when a priest does this to you, he robs you of your faith.
所以你要麼酗酒 要麼嗑藥
So you reach for the bottle or the needle,
而這些都不起作用時 你就只能縱身跳橋
or if those don't work, you jump off a bridge.
這就是我們稱自己為倖存者的原因
That's why we call ourselves survivors.
你們讀過詹森·內裏的書嗎
Have you read Jason Berry's book?
他寫了路易斯安那的高瑟案
He wrote about the gauthe case in Louisiana.
-怎麼寫 -g-a-u-t-h-e
- That's g-- - g-a-u-t-h-e.
來 去和理查德·賽普談談吧
Here. And talk to Richard sipe.
他在教會的其中一間治療中心工作
He worked in one of the church's treatment centers.
他以前是神父 娶了一位修女
He's an ex-priest. Married a nun.
這給你 這是科斯案的證詞
Here. This is his testimony from the kos case.
菲爾 治療中心是什麼
Phil, what's a treatment center?
就是當神父被抓到時會被送去的地方
It's where they send priests when they get caught.
我知道的都在這盒子裏了
This is all here in the box.
我五年前就寄給你們了
I sent this to you guys five years ago.
呃 寄給《環球報》嗎 你寄給誰了
Uh, to the globe? Who did you send it to?
我不想說是誰 但他們表示不感興趣
I don't wanna say who, but they said they weren't interested.
但我們確實做過幾篇關於你的報道 我在剪報裏看到了
But we did run a couple stories on you. I saw them in the clips.
嗯 可坦白說 那根本不夠
Yeah, but to be completely frank, it wasn't enough.
你們要明白
You guys gotta understand.
這事關重大
This is big.
這不僅關乎波士頓
This is not just Boston.
它關乎整個國家 整個世界
It's the whole country. It's the whole world.
它的矛頭直指梵蒂岡
And it goes right up to the Vatican.
你有證據嗎 菲爾
Do you have any proof of that, Phil?
不 還沒 但想想吧 他們數量這麼多
No. Not yet. But there are so many of them.
不然他們幹嘛要極力隱瞞這麼久
How else could they have hidden it for so long?
-什麼數量那麼多 -神父啊
- So many what? - Priests!
神父
Priests!
我知道僅波士頓就有十三個
I know of 13 right here in Boston.
你知道波士頓有十三個神父對兒童進行性騷擾嗎
You know 13 priests in Boston who have molested children?
是啊 你為什麼要重複我說的每句話
Yeah! Why do you keep repeating everything I say?
我只是想確認清楚
I just like to clarify things.
早在五年前我寄給你們這些東西的時候
Maybe you should have clarified
你們就該搞清楚了
it five years ago when I sent you all of this stuff.
都在這裏面了
It's all right here.
能借用一下洗手間嗎
May I use your bathroom?
嗯 好啊 菲爾 走吧
Yeah, sure, Phil. Come on.
你們怎麼看
Well, what do you think?
嗯 這傢伙有備而來 這點毫無疑問
Well, the guy's got an agenda, that's for sure.
-你這麼認為嗎 -他明顯經歷了很多
- You think? - He's obviously been through a lot.
但他很聰明 而且如果他關於十三個神父的話是對的
But he's smart, and if he's right about 13 priests--
嗯 但我們很難相信這個傢伙
yeah, it might be a big "If" With this guy.
調查一下他的背景
Do a background check on him.
追查一下他組織裏其它倖存者的情況
And follow up with some of the other survivors of his group.
我去找這位前神父 賽普
I'll track down this ex-priest, sipe.
好 但也要盯緊加拉貝迪安 那個更重要
Okay, but stay on garabedian. That's more important.
啊 加拉貝迪安 真是煩人
Ah. Garabedian. What a pain in the ass.
你也可以很煩人 麥克
You can be a pain in the ass, Mike.
嗯
Mmm.
米切爾 真巧啊 你還好嗎
Mitchell, what a surprise. How are you?
-我很好 雷贊德斯先生 -那就好
- I'm fine, Mr. Rezendes. - Good.
我還沒收到你的回電 我給你留了好多言
I haven't heard back from you. I left you a couple of messages.
我特別忙 沒什麼時間聽電話
I've been very busy. I-I don't have time for calls.
我想也是 聽著 聽著 米奇
I'm sure you don't. Listen, listen, Mitch.
讓我和幾位受害者談談吧
Let me talk to a couple of the victims.
採訪時你可以旁聽
You could sit in on the interview.
你要不滿意 隨時可以結束採訪
If you're not happy, you could kill it.
我和我的客戶談過了
I spoke to my clients.
他們不想上報 抱歉
They don't want to be in the press. I'm sorry.
我能理解 但我不會用真名的
I get that, but I don't need to name names.
-我不信任你 雷贊德斯先生 -我知道你不信我
- I don't believe you, Mr. Rezendes. - I'm sure you don't.
-聽著 米切爾 -不 雷贊德斯先生 拜託
- Listen, Mitchell. - Look, Mr. Rezendes, please--
我不是來給他們寫個人檔案的 我在做更重要的事
I'm not writing a profile here. I'm working on something bigger.
更重要 我不懂這是什麼意思
Bigger? I don't know what that means.
我不該告訴你這些
I'm not supposed to tell you this,
但我這些調查是為聚焦小組做的
but I'm digging around for spotlight.
-聚焦在關注這事 -嗯 我們正在調查
- Spotlight's on this? - Yeah, we're looking into it.
但你得幫我 你得讓我
But you gotta help me. You gotta
和那些受害者們談談 拜託
let me talk to some of these victims. Please.
拜託了
Please.
明早九點半再來吧
Come back tomorrow, 9:30 am.
謝謝
Thank you.
-法伊弗小姐 -喬
- Ms. Pfeiffer? - Joe?
哦 見鬼
Oh, shoot!
-沒事沒事 -抱歉 請坐
- That's okay. - Sorry. Please sit.
謝謝
Thank you.
-這位置可以嗎 -很好呀
- Is this table okay? - This is perfect.
我等您的時候吃了一塊鬆餅
I had a muffin while I was waiting.
其實是兩塊 我一緊張就吃東西
Two, actually. I eat when I'm nervous.
其實我也是誒
I do that too, actually.
希望我沒遲到 菲爾告訴我是一點
I hope I'm not late. Phil told me 1:00.
不 你沒遲到 是我來早了
No, you're fine. I got here early.
早了差不多一個小時
About an hour.
呃 你介意我做些筆記嗎 可以嗎
Um, would you mind if I took some notes? Would that be all right?
你不介意我做點筆記吧
You don't mind if I take some notes, do you?
-你會寫我的名字嗎 -不會
- Are you gonna use my name? - No.
如果你不想我寫 我就不寫
Not if you don't want me to, no.
我剛有了個孩子
I just had a kid.
他才一歲 但我不確定我是否想讓他知道這事
He's only one, but I'm not sure I want him to know about this.
嗯 我理解
Sure. I get that.
帕特裏克 你隨時都可以結束這個採訪 好嗎
You can stop this interview at any time, Patrick. All right?
好的
Okay. All right.
你可以記筆記
Go ahead with your notes.
好的 那麼
Okay. So, um--
第一次事發時你們住在哪裏
where'd you live when it first happened?
在海德公園另一邊的樓裏
In the projects, over in Hyde park.
是在超市那邊嗎
Over by the stop & shop?
嗯 你知道呀
Yeah. You know it?
嗯 我當過幾年出租車司機
Yeah, I drove a cab for a few years.
那裏很早開門 咖啡也難喝 對吧
Open early. Bad coffee, right?
嗯 大概吧
Yeah. I guess.
那時你幾歲
How old were you when it happened?
十二歲
I was 12.
就在我父親自殺後發生的
Just after my dad killed himself.
哦 天吶
Oh, geez.
他是個十足的人渣
He was a real piece of shit.
我母親 也不是很穩定
And my mom, she wasn't so stable either.
-什麼意思 -我是說她瘋了
- How do you mean? - I mean she was nuts.
她有精神分裂癥
She was a schizophrenic.
都一樣不是好人
Same shit.
你第一次遇到吉歐根是什麼時候
When did you first meet geoghan?
我姐姐 在鄧金甜甜圈店裏看到他
Well, my sister, she saw him over in the dunkin' donuts.
告訴他父親去世了 他馬上趕了過來
Tells him about my old man passing, and he rushed right over.
那個修女 芭芭拉
This nun, sister Barbara,
負責一個組織 專門接收問題家庭來的孩子
ran this group for kids from troubled families.
嗯 那個組織在哪裏
Mm-hmm. Where was that?
額 在多爾切斯特的聖安布羅斯
Uh, St. Ambrose in Dorchester.
好的
Okay.
就是她把我介紹給尚利神父的
She's the one who introduced me to father shanley.
他是街區的神父
He was a street priest.
留長髮 很時髦
Long hair. Very hip.
他邀我去他後灣區[波士頓上層社會住宅區]的公寓
He invited me to his apartment in back bay.
-後灣區哪裏 -燈塔街
- Where in back bay? - Beacon street.
-燈塔 好的 -你是本地人嗎
- Beacon. Okay. - Are you from here?
額 不是的 我在俄亥俄州長大 但我母親是南方人
Uh, no. I grew up in Ohio, but my mom's from southie.
好吧 所以你懂的 我之前從沒見過後灣區
All right, so you get it. I'd never even seen back bay.
那第一次見面後發生了什麼呢 喬
So what happened on that first visit, Joe?
呃 一開始他很好 很有趣 也很隨意
Well, he was very nice at first, very funny, very casual.
我覺得他看得出來我是同性戀
And I think he could tell I was gay,
他讓我看了他的手機 趴在嬰兒床上看的
so he showed me this mobile he had, like over a baby's crib.
-嗯 -但是給我看了很多不同的東西
- Mm-hmm. - But with different words.
什麼同性戀 跨性別 還有雙性戀
"Homosexual." "Transsexual." "Bisexual."
嗯 你那時知道自己是同性戀嗎 喬
Okay. And did you know you were gay at that time, Joe?
SSK字幕組
知道
Yeah.
SSK字幕組
但我沒有告訴任何人
But that wasn't information
在多爾切斯特沒人知道
I was sharing with anybody. Not in Dorchester.
嗯
Okay.
他讓你看了手機之後呢
So, what happened after he showed you the mobile?
呃 我有點被嚇到了
Well, I was a little freaked out.
我想他看出來了
I think he could tell.
於是他說 你知道嗎 我們來玩脫衣撲克會好一點哦
So he said, you know, what'll help is if we play strip poker.
毫無疑問我輸了
Of course I lost.
然後 額 事情就發生了
And, uh, things went on from there.
你能給我講講細節嗎
Can you tell me specifically what happened?
細節就是 他
Specifically, he--
他對我性騷擾
he molested me.
喬 我想這時候我們要很注意用語
Joe, I think that the language is gonna be so important here.
我們不能美化這件事 只說「性騷擾」是不夠的
We can't sanitize this. Just saying "Molest" Isn't enough.
人們得知道究竟發生了什麼
People need to know what actually happened.
-我們應該把這些打包帶走 -是的
- We should probably get these to go. - Right.
吉歐根來了 我母親 你知道 她
Geoghan shows up, and my mom, you know, she's--
她很激動
she's thrilled.
我是說 就像看到上帝似的 你懂吧
I mean, this was like god showing up, you know?
嗯 之後發生什麼了呢
Sure. Right. So what happened then?
你真的要聽這些破事嗎
You really want to hear this shit?
對 帕特裏克 我要聽
Yeah. Yeah, Patrick, I do.
他說帶我去吃冰激凌
He offers to take me to get ice cream.
你知道的 他是神父 我是小孩 所以我就去了
You know, he's a priest, I'm a kid, so I go.
嗯
Sure.
然後我們開車回家
So we're driving home and he--
他開始輕拍我的腿
he starts patting my leg and--
然後
you know, then...
他的手就滑過來了
His hand just slides right up and he--
然後抓住我的性器
he grabs my dick.
你知道嗎 我都呆住了
You know, I-- I just froze up.
我完全嚇呆了 動彈不得
I was fucking petrified. I-I couldn't move.
我不知道怎麼辦 那時我還是個孩子
I didn't know what to do. I was just a little kid.
嗯
Yeah.
你知道 我壓根都沒吃到冰激凌
You know, I never even touched my ice cream.
它就在我手裏融化了
It just melted down my arm.
那你 額
Did you, um--
那以後你還有見他嗎
did you see him again after that?
嗯
Yeah.
好了 可以了 這次就先說這麼多吧
All right. That's good. Let's stop there for now.
好
Sure.
他說這樣做能讓我更適應自己的身體
He said it was a way to make me more comfortable with my body.
嗯 那這之後呢
Mmm. So what happened after that?
嗯 他脫下自己的衣服說
Well, he took off his clothes and he said,
「我一直以來都很壓抑
"I've been so depressed,
但也許你能讓我開心點 幫我吹喇叭」
but maybe you can cheer me up and give me a blow job."
真是謙謙君子
Classy guy.
-那你照做了嗎 -我做了
- And did you? - Yeah.
我想你肯定在想
I know you must be thinking,
為什麼我會為一個比我
why would I ever do that to
大三十歲的奇葩做這種事
some creepy guy who's 30 years older than me?
但你要明白
But what you have to understand
這是我人生中第一次
is that this is the first time in my life
有人告訴我同性戀並沒有什麼錯
that someone told me that it was okay to be gay.
-而且他還是一個神父 -嗯
- And it was a priest. - Right.
所以你為他口交了
So you had oral sex.
你們有過性行為嗎
Did you have intercourse?
有
Yes.
不是當時 是後來
Not then, but later.
那讓我痛苦了很久
It really messed me up.
我現在清醒了 但那 那就是一切的開始
I'm sober now, but that-- that was the beginning of it all.
那讓我十分困惑 你懂吧
It's very confusing, you know,
通過這種方式瞭解性是什麼
to be introduced to sex like that and then--
然後喜歡上男人 實在是
and then to be attracted to men, it's--
抱歉 我就知道我會忍不住的
I'm sorry. I knew I was gonna do this.
-哦 抱歉 -沒關係
- Oh, I'm sorry. - Don't be sorry.
沒事了 喬 沒事了
It's okay, Joe. It's okay.
那裏是有一個教堂
Of course there is a church right there.
還有一個操場
And a playground.
喬 你有試過和誰講這些嗎
Joe, did you ever try and tell anyone?
和誰講呢 神父嗎
Like who? A priest?
能用一下你的電話嗎
Can I use your phone?
好的 你知道放在哪兒
Yeah, sure. You know where it is.
如果你想的話可以寫我的名字
You can use my name if you want.
謝謝 帕特裏克
Thanks, Patrick.
不要謝我 把那些混蛋抓住 好嗎
Don't thank me. Just get these assholes, will you?
他是其中的幸運兒
He's one of the lucky ones.
至少他還活著
He's still alive.
-要來杯茶嗎 薩夏 -不了 奶奶 謝謝
- Do you want a cup of tea, sacha? - I'm okay, Nana. Thanks.
-你好 -嗨 喬 我是薩夏·法伊弗
- Hello? - Hi, Joe. It's sacha pfeiffer.
-嗨 薩夏 你好嗎 -很好 謝謝
- Hi, sacha. How are you? - I'm good, thanks.
呃 聽著 喬 我只想再問一件事
Um, listen, Joe, I just wanted to follow up on one thing.
你向菲爾·薩維亞諾說過這些 是嗎
You talked to Phil saviano about all of this, right?
嗯 是的 我去過幾次斯納普的會議
Yeah, I did. I went to a couple of snap meetings.
菲爾有沒有建議你採取一些措施呢
And did Phil ever suggest you do anything about it?
沒有 會議也不是關於這些的
No. The meetings weren't really about that.
其中一些人找了律師
A couple of them had gone to a lawyer,
但我覺得不值得
but I didn't think it was worth it.
為什麼
Why not?
去那裏要填很多表 太耗費時間精力了
There were just so many forms to fill out. It was overwhelming.
他說最多也只能為我爭取到一點賠償 所以
And he said he could only get me a small settlement, so--
-誰說的 -那個律師說的
- wh-who said that? - The lawyer told me that.
所以你是有去見過律師
So you did go and see a lawyer?
嗯 但最後還是沒有用
Yeah, but I didn't end up using him,
所以我想這個也不重要吧
so I didn't think it was important.
抱歉 我沒有要隱瞞的意思
I'm sorry. I'm not trying to hide anything.
不 我知道的 喬
No, I-I-I know, Joe.
你還記得那個律師的名字嗎
Do you remember his name? The lawyer?
不 但菲爾可能會知道
No. But maybe Phil would know.
他在波特案時經常出鏡 長得也很帥
The guy was on TV a lot during the Porter case. He was handsome.
是埃裏克·麥克利什嗎
Was it Eric macleish?
嗯 就是他 麥克利什
Yeah, that's it. Macleish.
我覺得他很帥
I thought he was very handsome.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
我剛剛在新聞編輯室
I was just in the newsroom.
斯威尼法官確定了聽證會的日期
Judge sweeney set a date for the hearing.
-真的嗎 什麼時候 -兩周後
- Really? When? - Two weeks.
-在斯普林菲爾德 -哦
- In Springfield. - Oh.
卡內洛斯凱開始坐莊收注了 一注十塊
Canellos started a pool. Ten bucks to get in.
有人買《環球報》贏嗎
Anyone picking the globe?
他坐的莊是斯威尼要用多久來否決我們
He's only taking bets on how fast sweeney rules against us.
羅比
Robby.
-收到我的留言了嗎 -收到了
- Did you get my message? - I did.
看樣子尚利神父就是我們的第四位了
Looks like father shanley could be our fourth priest.
嗯 我想是的
Yeah, I think he is.
-你追查麥克利什了嗎 -我剛剛和菲爾談過了
- Did you follow up with macleish? - I just talked to Phil.
他說麥克利什處理了很多這種案子
He said macleish dealt with a number of these cases.
-看來他忘記說了 -嗯
- Guess he forgot to mention that. - Yeah.
明天我要去法庭
I'm gonna go to the courthouse tomorrow,
看看能不能找到他經手的起訴教會的案子
see if I can find any cases he settled against the church.
好的 找到了給我電話 晚安
All right. Call me after you do. Good night.
好的 晚安
Okay. Good night.
嗨
Hey.
-你想 談談嗎 -嗯
- You wanted to, uh, chat? - Yeah.
-我吃晚飯要遲到了 不如送我一下吧 -好的
- I'm late for a dinner. Wanna walk me out? - Sure.
-天吶 這些人都不回家的嗎 -顯然不
- Geez. Does that guy ever go home? - Apparently not.
還有些人不坐穿編輯室的椅子
I got guys who won't leave till he does.
是絕對不會離開的
He's wearing out the goddamn newsroom.
-吉歐根案的進展如何 -正在追查更多的受害者
- Where are we on geoghan? - Following up on more victims.
-我想擴大調查範圍 -為什麼
- I want to expand the investigation. - Why?
我們已經找到四個神父了 說不准真的有十三個
We got a fourth priest. There might be as many as 13.
-十三個 -是啊
- Thirteen? - Yeah.
-你的料從哪來的 -菲爾·薩維亞諾
- Who's your source? - Phil saviano.
老天啊 羅比 我告訴過
Jesus Christ, robby. I told
-麥克那傢伙可是 -我知道 我知道
- Mike that guy's a fuckin'-- - I know, I know.
我覺得薩維亞諾可能是可信的 本
I think saviano might be legit, Ben.
想給我解釋一下嗎
Want to elaborate on that?
不 還不行
No. Not really.
只是覺得事情彷彿越發複雜了 我的直覺
It just feels like this thing's stacking up. That's my gut.
-好吧 -好的
- Okay. - Okay. Good.
謝謝
Thank you.
你好
Hello?
雷贊德斯先生
Mr. Rezendes?
呃 我是 你是哪位
Uh, yeah. Who's this?
我是理查德·賽普
It's Richard sipe
噢 嗨 理查德 你還好嗎
Oh, yeah. Hey, Richard. How are you?
-我很好 -額 謝謝你打電話過來
- I'm good. - Uh, thanks for calling.
額 菲爾·薩維亞諾給了我你的名字
Look, uh, Phil saviano g-gave me your name.
我在想能不能問你幾個問題
I was wondering if I could ask you a few questions.
-當然可以 -好極了
- Of course. Yeah. - Great.
菲爾說你以前在一個巴爾的摩的
Uh, so Phil told me that you were working
一個教會治療中心工作
a-at one of the church's treatment centers in Baltimore.
是的 西頓精神科研究所
Yes. The seton psychiatric institute.
由仁愛修女會運營
It was run by the daughters of charity.
那是什麼時候 理查德
And, uh, when was that, Richard?
我1965年加入了這個研究所
Well, I started my psychotherapy fellowship there in 1965,
-恩 -我在那裏呆了五年
- okay. - And I was there for five years,
但接下來我花了三十年
but I spent the next 30
研究性侵別人的神父和那些受害者
studying abusive priests and their victims.
-真的嗎 -恩
- Really? - Mm-hmm.
所以你一直關注的就只有這個嗎
And that's-- that's been your sole focus?
聽著 麥克 教會想讓
Look, Mike, the church wants
大家覺得裏面只有幾隻害群之馬
us to believe that it's just a few bad apples.
但這只是冰山一角
But it's a much bigger problem than that.
問題有多嚴重 理查德
How much bigger, Richard?
根據我的調查
Well, based on the research,
我將它歸為一種可識別的精神現象
I would classify it as a recognizable psychiatric phenomenon.
可真是大問題啊
That's big.
-嘿 麥可 -嘿
- Hey, Mac. - Hey.
如果我想要一個神父的歷史資料
If I wanted historical data on a priest,
想知道他所分配的教區
parishes he's been assigned to,
我在哪裏可以找到這些資料
where would I find that?
吉歐根那件案子嗎 都在那些剪報裏
The geoghan case? It's all in the clips.
麗莎有資料
Lisa has the source material.
如果是另一個神父呢
What if it was for another priest,
沒有上過報紙的
one that hadn't been in the papers?
你在找另一個神父 誰啊
You're looking at another priest? Who you looking at?
有辦法嗎
Any ideas?
拜託 馬特 你不打算告訴我嗎
Come on, Matt. You're not gonna tell me?
我要去開會了 謝謝你 麥可 你好啊 史蒂夫
I gotta get to a meeting. Thanks, Mac. Hey, Steve.
總教區出版了年度名錄
The archdiocese puts out an annual directory,
每個神父和教區都有記錄
every priest and parish.
好極了
That's great.
有98年以前的嗎
Do these go back any further than '98?
恩 一直到八十年代
Oh, yeah. Going back to the '80s in the mez.
更早以前的話 你得去波士頓公共圖書館了
Beyond that, you gotta go to bpl.
-謝了 麗莎 -不客氣
- The mez, huh? Thanks, Lisa. - You bet.
他說他們的目標是同一種孩子
He said they all target the same kind of kid.
家庭收入低 沒有父親 家庭支離破碎
Low-income families, absentee fathers, broken homes.
因此吉歐根這種人
So a guy like geoghan
找上這些男孩不是因為他偏愛他們
goes after boys not because he prefers them,
而是因為這些男孩更懂羞恥 不喜歡說話
but because they have more shame, less likely to talk.
恩
Hmm.
-這些人就是禽獸 羅比 -嗯
- These guys are predators, robby. - Yeah.
我和賽普談過了
I-I-I talked to sipe.
他說在六十年代的西頓研究所見過許多這樣的神父
He said he's seen dozens of them in the '60s in seton.
他稱之為一種「現象」
He called it a "Phenomenon."
-他為什麼沒有揭示於眾 -他有
- Why didn't he go public? - He did.
但教會竭力敗壞了他的名聲
But the church made a huge effort to discredit him.
惡意宣傳 有威望的主教還發表公開聲明
Smear campaigns, public statements by prominent bishops.
就像薩維亞諾和加拉貝迪安說的一樣
It's just like saviano said. And garabedian.
-你有什麼進展嗎 -找到更多的受害者
- You getting anywhere with him? - More victims.
更多的受害者 你沒有問到底嗎
More victims. You can't empty his pockets?
我會盡力的 但是要更多時間
I'll get to him. I just need more time.
拜託了 麥克 你得搞定他
Come on, Mike. You gotta get him.
我會的 我會的
I'll get him. I'll get him.
天吶 這是什麼怪味
Jesus. What the hell is that smell?
角落裏有一隻死老鼠
There's a dead rat in the corner.
-你找到了什麼 -教會的名錄
- What have you got? - Church directories.
上面有馬薩諸塞州每個神父的名字
It's every priest in Massachusetts,
還有他們所在的教區
what parish they're assigned to.
-是官方資料嗎 -恩 我覺得可以在裏面
- Are these official? - Yeah. I figured it could help us track down
找到一些薩維亞諾提到過的神父
some of the priests saviano mentioned,
也許能找到更多的受害者
maybe find some more victims.
-能開點燈嗎 -我找不到開關
- Can we turn on some more lights? - I couldn't find the switch.
-你要我的眼鏡嗎 -不 不用
- You wanna borrow my glasses? - No, I'm good. I'm good.
看 1983年
Look. 1983.
約翰·吉歐根 多切斯特聖布蘭登街教區
John geoghan, St. Brendan's parish, Dorchester.
我們可以找到任何一年的任何神父嗎
So we can find out where any priest is in any given year?
恩 我找到了
Yeah, I got him here at--
-哈 -什麼
- huh. - What?
1980年 吉歐根從教區離職
1980. The year geoghan was pulled from jp.
上面說他在休病假
It says he's on sick leave.
不會吧 真的嗎
Come on. It really says that?
1991年的在哪裏
Where is, uh, 1991?
這裏
Yeah. Here ya go.
我看看利亞姆·巴雷特
Let me see this. Barrett. Barrett. Liam.
我看不清 幫我找找利亞姆·巴雷特
I can't read that. Look for a Liam Barrett in there.
1991年他從查爾斯頓離職
1991's the year they pulled him out of charlestown.
「利亞姆·巴雷特」
"Barrett, Liam."
-恩 -「休病假」
- Yeah. - "Sick leave."
這是官方說法
It's an official designation.
把這些拿到樓上
Let's get these upstairs.
馬特 你查查看薩維亞諾告訴我們的神父
Matt, check on those priests saviano gave us.
-我是羅比 -我在法庭
- Robby. - I'm down at the courthouse.
有點不對勁
Something's not right here.
-尚利的也沒有 薩夏 -好的 謝謝
- Nothing on shanley either, sacha. - Okay, thanks.
-我們得再找麥克利什談話 -真的嗎 為什麼
- Um, we need to talk to macleish again. -Really. Why?
這裏什麼也沒有 任何記錄都沒有
Huh? There's nothing here. There aren't any records.
多謝等待 抱歉夥計們 我一直在接電話
Thanks for waiting. So sorry, guys. Stuck on a call.
-沒事 你怎麼樣 -很好
- Not a problem. How are you? - Good.
-謝謝和我們會面 -應該的 什麼事
- Thanks for meeting us. - You bet. What's up, guys?
麥克利什先生 你認識一個叫保羅·尚利的神父嗎
Mr. Macleish, are you familiar with a priest named Paul shanley?
恩 我認識
Yes, I am familiar with him.
你有處理過尚利神父的案子嗎
And have you settled cases against father shanley?
你們能理解的 我不能告訴你們
As I'm sure you can understand, I can't discuss that with you.
恩 那羅納德·帕奎因神父呢
Yeah, h-how about, uh, father Ronald paquin?
我也不能告訴你們 拜託了
Well, I can't discuss that with you either. Come on, guys.
我們知道你幫他們處理過幾場官司
We understand you've settled several cases against each of them.
即使我是有參與這些官司
Even if I'd been involved in those cases,
調解結果也是保密的
the settlements would be confidential
如果我說出來的話 會被取消律師資格
and I could be disbarred for acknowledging their existence.
-好嗎 -恩
- Okay? - Mm-hmm.
聽著 我說過這些案子很棘手
Look, I told you guys these are tough cases.
大多數人只想他們承認
Most of these folks, they just want some acknowledgment
發生了什麼事情
of what happened.
讓他們和主教坐下來 拿點鈔票
We got 'em a sit-down with the bishop and a little dough,
這是最好的結果了
and that's the best they could hope for.
當然了 這是神父所期待的最好結果
Well, it's certainly the best the priests could hope for.
不 教會保證了
No, the church promised
他們會開除這些神父
they'd take the priests out of circulation.
你有後續跟進嗎
And did you follow up on that?
你們還有什麼事嗎
Do you guys need anything else?
有 為什麼沒有任何記錄
Yes. Why aren't there any records?
我之前在法庭
I was down at the courthouse earlier.
那裏沒有任何關於這些調解結果的記錄
There aren't any records of any of these settlements.
我們直接和教會溝通的
We dealt directly with the church.
我們起草一份交款通知書 送到了主教辦公室
We would draw up a demand letter and send it to the chancery.
-你沒在法院上提交過任何文件嗎 -這是私人調解
- You never filed anything in court? - It's a private mediation.
那麼 這只是
So, this is just you
你和總教區的律師在操作嗎
and the archdiocese's lawyers in a room?
-是的 -還有其他人嗎
- Correct. - Anyone else?
有時候教會會請
Occasionally the church would
其他辯護律師來幫忙
bring in another defense attorney to help out.
你知道他們的名字嗎
You have names?
不 我不知道
Nope. No, I don't.
那這一切都是私下操縱咯
So this was all under the table?
根本沒有文件可循
There's no paper trail at all.
為了達成私下和解
The victim has to sign a
受害者不得不簽保密協議
confidentiality agreement to get the settlement.
律師作為第三方 然後教會隱瞞真相
The lawyer takes a third, and the church sweeps it under the rug.
-這完全是非法的啊 -事情還要更複雜
- It's a freakin' racket. - It's more complicated than that.
麥克利什有責任
Macleish has got a duty
讓客戶得到最好的結果
to the client to get the best deal he can.
當然 但他們要代表多少受害者
Sure. But how many victims do you
從中獲取多少利益才能出手幫忙
represent and profit from before you say something?
加拉貝迪安會說一個也沒有
Garabedian would say none.
這就是為什麼他要把這些案子送上法庭
That's why he's taking these cases to court.
-他想要人們知道這件事 -我同意
- He wants people to know about this. - I agree.
本 先把法律道德放一邊
And legal ethics aside, Ben,
像麥克利什這樣的處理方式
I mean, operating the way macleish has
只會讓這些侵害案件不為人知
all but guarantees that the abuse stays under wraps.
恩 麥克利什確認了薩維亞諾說的那些神父嗎
Yeah. Did macleish confirm all saviano's priests?
沒有 他受到了保密協議的限制
No. He's limited by his confidentiality agreement.
但他顯然調解了很多神父的案子
But clearly he's settled cases against a number of them.
菲爾讓我聯繫到了一些其他受害者
Phil's put me in touch with some of the other victims.
我相信能找到所有神父
I'm pretty confident all of his priests are gonna check out.
所以是有十三個神父嗎
So it is 13 priests?
-恩 -看起來是這樣
- Yeah. - Looks that way.
天吶
Holy shit.
好的 繼續努力
Okay. Keep going.
抱歉 你叫什麼
I'm sorry. What was the name again?
額 巴倫
Uh, baron.
B-a-r-o-n
B-a-r-o-n.
我沒找到 等一會兒
I'm having trouble finding it. Just give me a second.
沒事了 金姆 我為他擔保
It's okay, Kim. I can vouch for him.
我是皮特·康利 天主教慈善會的董事
I'm Pete conley. I'm on the board of catholic charities.
歡迎來到波士頓 巴倫先生
Welcome to Boston, Mr. Baron.
-謝謝 -感謝你加入我們
- Thank you. - I appreciate you joining us.
我們對在波士頓所做的工作感到很自豪
We're very proud of the work we do here in Boston.
主教說你之前跟他見過面 聊得挺愉快的
Oh, the cardinal said you had a nice visit.
是的 沒錯
Yes, we did.
他是個很了不起的人 很高興你們有機會能一起談話
He's an extraordinary man. I'm glad you had a chance to chat.
玩得開心嗎
Enjoying yourself?
老實說 我不太擅長參加這些活動
Uh, to be honest, these events aren't really my strong suit.
-恩 -你參加了慈善會嗎
- Yeah. - Are you involved with the charity?
沒有 我有些朋友參加了
Not directly, no. Several of my friends are.
我們都讀的波士頓天主教高中
We all went to high school at bc high.
就在《環球報》的對面
That's the school across the street from the globe.
-很容易看到嘛 -恩
- It's hard to miss. - Yeah.
而且逃課還很容易被抓到
Hard to get away from too, apparently.
如果你想見紅衣主教的話
The, uh, cardinal's in the corner,
他就在那邊
if you're so inclined.
-我們見過了 -真的嗎
- We've met. - Really?
他有提到起訴嗎
Did he mention the suit?
沒有 但他給了我一本《教義問答書》
No, but he did give me a copy of the catechism.
好吧
Yeah.
他的精明並不是眾人皆知的
Well, the cardinal's not known for his subtlety.
在調查波特的時候
During the Porter investigation,
他真的借用了神的力量對《環球報》進行壓制
he literally called down the power of god on the globe.
此話怎講
How'd that play out?
一周後 我們的編輯在滑雪時摔斷了腿
A week later, our editor broke his leg skiing.
要鮮蝦吐司嗎 先生們
Shrimp toast, gentlemen?
-不 謝謝 -謝謝
- Uh, no, thanks. - Thanks.
你說有個受害人提起了刑事訴訟嗎
You said one of the victims filed a criminal complaint?
恩 有一些
Yeah, there were a few of them.
但是教會的同伴起訴後
But the judge had the case records sealed
法官就密封了案件記錄
after friends of the church complained.
而且教會的人脈眾多
And the church has a lot of friends.
比如埃裏克·麥克利什嗎
Like Eric macleish?
恩
Yeah.
我只能說他嘴太嚴了 我們得找別的方法
Let's just say he's not part of the solution.
-你聽懂我的意思了嗎 -當然
- You follow what I'm saying? - Sure.
你工作真賣力 雷贊德斯先生
You work hard, Mr. Rezendes.
-你結婚了嗎 -恩
- Are you married? - Yeah.
你妻子不介意你
Your wife doesn't mind you
-整天工作嗎 -噢 她介意
- working all the time? - Oh, yeah, she does.
這就是為什麼我沒有結婚 我太忙了
That's why I never got married. I'm too busy.
我的工作太重要了
What I do is too important.
恩
Mmm.
你們的新編輯是個猶太人 對嗎
Your new editor, he's a Jew, right?
恩 是的
That's right. Yeah.
你看 他一進來
Well, see, he comes in
大家突然都對教會有了興趣
and suddenly everybody's interested in the church.
你知道為什麼嗎
You know why? Mmm.
因為他是旁觀者清 跟我一樣
Because it takes an outsider, like me.
我是亞美尼亞人
I'm Armenian.
你認識多少在波士頓的亞美尼亞人
How many Armenians do you know in Boston?
史蒂夫·柯吉恩 在《環球報》上班
Steve kurkjian. Works at the globe.
噢 你認識兩個了 真該給你頒個獎
Oh. That's two. You should get a prize or something.
-你是哪裏人 意大利人嗎 -不 我是葡萄牙人
- What are you, Italian? - No, I'm Portuguese.
-哪裏來的 -波士頓東區
- From where? - Uh, east Boston.
真的嗎 波士頓東區
Really? East Boston?
你口音聽起來不像啊
You don't sound like it.
這座城市 這些人
This city, these people--
讓我們這些外來人覺得沒有歸屬感
making the rest of us feel like we don't belong.
但他們並不比我們優秀
But they're no better than us.
看看他們如何對待孩子的吧
Look at how they treat their children.
記住我的話 雷贊德斯先生
Mark my words, Mr. Rezendes,
原句出自非洲古諺語「撫養一個孩子需要全村的努力」
環境可以塑造一個孩子
if it takes a village to raise a child,
也可以毀了一個孩子
it takes a village to abuse one.
嘿 你來了
Hey, here he is.
-要喝酒嗎 -樂意之至
- Want a beer? - Love one.
再來一杯
Another.
-和芭芭拉一起來的嗎 -不 她不喜歡來這些地方
- You here with Barbara? - No, no. She hates these things.
凱倫也是
Karen too. Yeah.
女人真聰明
Smart ladies.
-乾杯 -乾杯
- Slente. - Slente.
我見到了你的新編輯
Mmm. I met your new editor.
看起來是個不錯的人
Seemed like a decent fellow.
我覺得是的
I think he is.
嘿 前些天我和埃裏克·麥克利什
Hey, I had an interesting conversation
談了一些有趣的東西
with Eric macleish the other day.
原來多年來他一直
Turns out he's been settling
在幫總教區調解性侵兒童案
abuse cases with the archdiocese for years.
你真的想在這裏談這個嗎
You really want to talk about this here?
吉姆 你說你幫了巴雷特神父當是人情
Jim, you said you helped out on father Barrett as a favor.
只有那一次嗎
That was a one-off?
你還參與了多少件案子
How many of these cases you been involved with?
你知道我不能回答 羅比 這是違反職業道德的
You know I can't answer that, robby. It's unethical.
真的僅僅因為這個嗎
Is that all it is?
這就是我一直有所耳聞
So, this would be the robby Robinson
但卻素未謀面的羅比·羅賓森
I've always heard about but never met.
哈
Huh?
聽我說 吉米
Listen to me, Jimmy.
你得選對邊
You want to be on the right side of this.
你說的可是教會啊 羅比
This is the church you're talking about, robby.
看看四周 他們都是好人
Look around. These are good people.
為這座城市做了很多好事
Done a lot of good for this city.
你就好好玩吧
Enjoy the party.
我現在看了很多名錄
I've been through a lot of these now.
他們將這些神父開除時
"Sick leave" Isn't the only designation they use
不光會聲稱「休病假」
when they take one of these priests out of circulation.
他們用一堆說法 「未出席」
They use a slew of terms: "Absent on leave,"
「未分配」 「應急響應」
"Unassigned," "Emergency response."
-這些人什麼詞都用上了 -除了強姦
- They got a word for everything, these guys. - Except rape.
而且他們比其他神父更頻繁地更換教區
And they move parishes way more frequently than other priests.
在我小時候
When I was a kid, a priest moved
一個神父過了七八年才走 有時候更久
after seven or eight years, sometimes longer.
這些人頂多兩三年就走了
These guys, it's two to three years tops.
薩維亞諾說的神父後面都是這麼寫的嗎
And did they use these designations for all of saviano's priests?
恩 這是個很明顯的模式
Yeah. It's a pretty clear pattern.
夥計們 賽普打電話來了
Guys, I got sipe.
我覺得如果你們真的想理解這場危機
I think if you really want to understand the crisis,
你們要先從禁慾需求開始著手
you need to start with the celibacy requirement.
那是我的第一個主要發現
That was my first major finding.
只有一半的神父是禁慾的
Only 50% of the clergy are celibate.
現在大多數神父都和其他成人有過性行為
Now, most of them are having sex with other adults.
但這樣子卻創造了一種容忍甚至是保護
But the fact remains that this creates a culture of secrecy
其中的戀童癖者的風氣
that tolerates and even protects pedophiles.
那麼你覺得教會知道
So you believe the church
這件事的嚴重程度嗎
is aware of the extent of this, uh, crisis?
噢 當然
Oh, absolutely.
在路易斯安那州首先爆出醜聞後
After the first major scandal in Louisiana,
教廷大使的秘書兼教律學家和湯姆·多伊爾
tom Doyle, the secretary canonist for the papal nuncio,
共同創作了一份報告 警告戀童癖的神父
co-authored a report warning pedophile priests
若犯了此罪 則要承擔賠償上億美元的法律責任
were a billion-dollar liability.
那是1985年
That was in 1985.
1985年
1985?
是的
That's right.
誰看了那份報告 有天主教會的人嗎
Who saw that report? Anyone from the catholic hierarchy?
當然 多伊爾想把這份報告
Sure. Doyle tried to introduce the report
在天主教全國主教會議上公佈出來
at the national conference of catholic bishops.
事實上 當時勞主教為這份報告提供了資金
In fact, cardinal law initially helped to fund the report.
但之後他退縮了 然後他們擱置了此事
But then he backed out and they shelved it.
-他在開玩笑嗎 -理查德 我是羅比
- Is he kidding me? - Uh, Richard, robby here.
我們覺得波士頓有十三個符合此模式的神父
We think we have 13 priests in Boston that fit this pattern,
這會是一個大新聞
which would be a very-- a very big story.
你覺得有這麼多人嗎
Does that sound right to you, uh, in terms of scale?
不 羅比 在我看來是太少了
No, not really, robby. Sounds low to me.
我估計至少有百分之六對兒童有過性侵行為
My estimates suggest six percent act out sexually with minors.
百分之六什麼
Uh, six percent of what?
百分之六的神父
Six percent of all priests.
波士頓有多少神父
How many priests do we have in Boston?
大概一千五百個 百分之一是十五個
About 1,500. One percent is 15.
百分之六是 九十
Six percent is... 90.
什麼 九十個神父
Wait. Nine-ninety priests?
這有可能嗎
Is that possible?
從數量上來看 是的
From a metric standpoint, yes.
那和我的發現是一致的
That would certainly be in line with my findings.
-喂 -額
- Hello? - Uh--
波士頓有九十個這樣的神父
ninety fucking priests? In Boston?
他是這麼說的
That's what he said.
如果有九十個這樣的混蛋 人們會知道的
If there were 90 of these bastards, people would know.
也許他們知道
Maybe they do.
但大家都緘默不語嗎
And no one said a thing?
大家都是友好的德國人
Good Germans.
我想你這話可不能在外說
I don't think that's a comparison you want to make publicly.
麥克利什知道 他只是什麼都沒說
Macleish knew. He just didn't say anything.
那是十三個神父
That's 13 priests.
十三和九十之間差別很大的
There's a big difference between 13 and 90.
賽普從哪裏得知的這些數字
Where's this guy sipe getting his numbers?
他對此研究了三十年
Well, he's been studying it for 30 years.
-他是一位專業的精神治療醫師 -好的
- He is a trained psychotherapist. - Okay.
但我們不能全都聽信一個
But we need something
以前是神父 還和一個尼姑結婚的嬉皮士
more than a metric from some hippie ex-priest
我們還需要更多證據
who's shacking up with a nun.
好 那我們就再找些受害者 這樣就能找到更多神父
Okay, so we'll track down more victims. We'll get more priests.
然後我們可以用名錄找到他們
Then we could check them against the directories.
-受害者這麼多 -我們會找到的
- That's a shitload of victims. - We'll get there.
要多久
How long's it gonna take?
太久了
Too long.
等等 會議結束了嗎
Wait. Meeting's over?
目前是的
Yeah, for now.
-你有什麼辦法 -要是我們反著來呢
- What've you got? - What if we work backwards?
-什麼意思 反著做什麼 -查名錄
- What do you mean? From what? - From the directories.
我們一直在用名錄確認行為不端的神父
We've been using them to confirm bad priests.
如果我們反著來呢
What if we do it the other way around?
-用名錄來追查行為不端的神父 -正是
- Use the directories to identify bad priests. - Yeah, exactly.
我們去找那些說法
We search by designation. We
找標記著「休病假」或「未分配」的所有神父
look for any priest on "Sick leave" Or "Unassigned."
-或者搬過很多次的神父 -恩
- Or have been moved around a lot. - Yeah.
-那要費很多精力吧 -大家一起干就好了
- It's gonna take a load of work. - Well, not if we're all on it.
你也來嗎
You too?
-通常來說 「大家」肯定包含了我啊 -對 通常來說是這樣
- Generally that's what "All" Means. - Yeah, generally.
休病假
未分配
任職中
圖書館要關門了
Library is closing.
治療中心
佩爾頓街 276號房
我擦
Holy shit.
不可能吧
No freakin' way.
孩子們
不要接近佩爾頓街的276號房
也不要接近住在裏面的人
-塔爾博特 -恩
- Talbot. - Yep.
-蒂夫南 -恩
- Tivnan. - Yep.
-托馬 -恩
- Toma. - Yep.
-特恩布爾 -恩
- Turnbull. - Yep.
-沃爾什 -恩
- Walsh. - Yep.
-威爾斯 恩
- Welsh. - Yep.
-就這些了 -就這些了
- That's it. - That's it.
-天吶 -羅比
- Holy shit. - Robby.
和賽普估計的只差三個 簡直難以置信
That's three off sipe's estimate. That's incredible.
羅比
Robby.
-有多少個 -八十七個
- How many? - Eighty-seven.
波士頓有八十七個神父
Eighty-seven priests in Boston.
-給麥克利什打電話 我要找他談談 -好
- Call macleish. I wanna talk to him. - Okay.
-能打印出來嗎 -當然可以
- Can you print it? - Sure can.
吉姆·蘇利文的辦公室
Jim Sullivan's office.
我是沃爾特·羅賓森 我找吉姆·蘇利文
Yeah, Walter Robinson for Jim Sullivan.
請告訴他有要事 拜託了
Tell him it's important, please.
請稍等
One moment, please.
嘿 羅比 還好嗎
Hey, robby. Everything okay?
我要你告訴我一些事情 吉姆
I need you to tell me something, Jim.
-有九十個神父嗎 -什麼
- Could it be 90 priests? - What?
有九十個神父這麼多嗎
Could it be as high as 90?
天吶 羅比
Jesus, robby.
我必須得知道 吉姆 如果不重要的話我是不會問的
I need to know, Jim. I wouldn't be asking if it wasn't important.
你得收手了 羅比
You gotta stop this, robby.
羅比 麥克利什的助手說
Robby, macleish's assistant
他時間排滿了 沒法見我們
said he's all booked up. He can't see us.
好吧 去他的
Yeah. Well, the hell he can't.
好的 這會很有意思的
All right. That'll be fun.
我待會來找你 好嗎
You know what? I'll catch up with you, okay?
-好的 -嘿
- Okay. - Hey.
真的很抱歉 我現在沒時間談話
I'm really sorry. I am. I don't have any time to talk right now--
麥克利什先生 我們有理由相信
Mr. Macleish, we have reason to believe
波士頓有八十七位神父
that there are allegations
都受過指控
against as many as 87 priests in Boston.
我不能和你們談這些
I can't talk to you about that.
-這個數字對嗎 -你在開玩笑吧
- Does that number sound right to you? - You gotta be kidding me.
我說過了 我現在沒時間閒扯
I just told you I don't have time for this crap now.
埃裏克 你調解了多少個神父
Eric, how many priests did you settle?
羅比 你知道我不能告訴你
Robby, you know I can't tell you that.
你得把神父和受害者的名字都給我
You're gonna give me the names and the names of their victims.
額
Um--
你是在威脅我嗎
are you threatening me?
我們現在有兩條新聞
We've got two stories here.
一條新聞是關於那些可惡的神父
We've got a story about degenerate clergy,
另一條則是關於一幫律師
and we've got a story about a bunch of lawyers
他們把性侵兒童案當成了家庭手工業
turning child abuse into a cottage industry.
你想我們報道哪條新聞
Now, which story do you want us to write?
因為我們必須要選一條
'Cause we're writing one of 'em.
我已經給你寄了一份名單
I already sent you a list of names.
你在說什麼 寄給了誰
What are you talking about? To whom?
幾年前 寄給了《環球報》
The globe. Years ago.
波特的案子發生後 我接到了很多電話
After the Porter case, I got plenty of calls.
光是波士頓就有二十個牽扯其中的神父
I had 20 priests in Boston alone,
但沒有媒體的幫助 我無法調查他們
but I couldn't go after them without the press.
因此我給了你們一份名單
So I sent you guys a list of names,
你們卻置若罔聞
and you buried it.
-我明天就要這些名字 -去你的剪報裏找吧 羅比
- I want those names tomorrow. - Check your goddamn clips, robby.
-我們在剪報裏什麼也沒找到 -是啊 真讓人吃驚
- We didn't find anything in the clips. - Yeah. Big surprise.
理查德 額 你還在做彌撒嗎
Richard, uh, do you still go to mass?
不 我已經有一陣子沒去教堂了
No. No, I haven't been to church for some time now.
但我還是個天主教徒
But I still consider myself a catholic.
這怎麼行得通呢
H-how does that work?
教會是一個由人組成的機構 麥克
Well, the church is an institution, Mike, made of men.
它是短暫的
It's passing.
但我的信仰是永恆的
My faith is in the eternal.
我試著把兩者區分開來
I try to separate the two.
-聽起來很難 -的確
- Sounds tricky. - It is.
特別是教會還在對我窮追猛打
Especially since the church continues to go after me.
代價很大的 麥克
It takes a toll, Mike.
他們想要鎮壓所有站出來說話的人
They'll try to silence anyone who speaks out.
我想他們很快就會找上你和你的團隊
I'm sure they'll come after you and your team soon enough.
真的嗎 那你覺得他們會怎麼做
Really. And how do you think they'd do that?
喂
Hello?
理查德
Richard?
誰啊
Who is it?
坎特伯雷大主教
It's the archbishop of canterbury.
我在披薩店吃了晚飯 剩了一些
I had dinner at santarpio's. Had some leftovers.
啊 你太棒了 謝啦
Ah, you're the freakin' best. Thanks.
-要喝酒嗎 -要
- You want a beer? - Yeah.
好的
You got it.
天吶 你還要在這個鬼地方住多久
Jesus. How much longer you gonna be in this shithole?
還在想呢
Yeah. I'm working on it.
她是個好女孩 麥克
She's a good girl, Mike.
是的 我們會解決的
Yeah, she is. We'll figure it out.
我最近沒什麼時間
I haven't had a lot of time lately.
其實我剛剛才和賽普通完電話
I just got off the phone with sipe, actually.
你親眼見過這個人嗎
Have you met this guy in person yet?
沒有 不過他對此事的瞭解明顯跟我們不在一個層次
No, but his knowledge of this is on a whole other level.
我要餓死了
I'm frickin' starving.
九十個神父的事查得怎麼樣了
So, where are we with the 90?
快了
We're close.
-多快 -就是快了
- How close? - We're close.
直接回答問題 好嗎
Just answer the question, will you?
我們查到了八十七個
We got 87 names.
正在努力確認 我們會查清楚的
We're trying to get confirmation. I think we will.
你在心煩什麼
Something bugging you?
我只是很驚訝
It's just surprising, that's all.
恩 是啊
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
大家都是
For everybody.
等等 本 我忘了問你
Wait, Ben. I forgot to ask you.
菲爾·薩維亞諾說
Phil saviano said he sent
幾年前他給《環球報》寄了一些資料
a bunch of info over to the globe years ago.
-你知道寄給誰了嗎 -不知道 怎麼了
- Do you have any idea to who? - No. Why?
我好奇罷了 我想知道
I'm just curious. I wanted to
你們有沒有漏掉什麼線索
see if there's any leads you guys didn't run out.
薩維亞諾五年前是個
Saviano was a fucking train
操蛋的麻煩鬼 我們沒有漏了什麼
wreck five years ago. We didn't miss anything.
這件事得有聚焦的追查
This story needed spotlight.
對 我同意 我只是在跟蹤調查
Yeah, I agree. I'm just following up.
-晚安 -嗯 晚安
- Good night. - Yeah, good night.
難以置信 你什麼時候搞到這個的
This is unbelievable. When did you get this?
麥克利什今天早上發郵件給我的
Macleish e-mailed the list this morning.
他處理了涉及四十五個神父的案件
He settled cases against 45 priests.
我們追查勞的事怎麼樣了
Where are we on Law?
有線索顯示他知道這件事嗎
Anything that shows he had knowledge of this?
我們還在對付加拉貝迪安 但沒有具體消息
We're still working garabedian. But nothing concrete.
我一直在想我們那天晚上的對話
I keep thinking about that conversation we had the other night
關於在我們報道波特案的時候
about how Law called down the power of god
勞是如何借用神的力量的
when we reported on Porter.
那就是勞的本性
That's just Law being Law.
好吧 但我查了剪報
Okay. But I checked the clips, and,
呃 波特甚至都不在波士頓教區
uh, Porter isn't even in the Boston archdiocese.
他來自福爾裏弗市 所以 為什麼反應這麼激烈
He's from fall river. So... why the extreme reaction?
勞肯定知道
Law had to know.
所以他的反應才這麼激烈
That's why he had the reaction.
因為他知道還有其他人
Because he knew there were others.
我覺得這就是我要的更重要的故事
I think that's the bigger story.
等等 比五十個神父還重要嗎
Wait. Bigger than 50 priests?
如果它是至上而下的操作 是的
If it came from the top down, yes.
但這數字明顯
But the numbers clearly
暗示了還有更高級的神職人員牽扯進去
indicate that there were senior clergy involved.
但是現在這些也只能是暗示
That's all they do-- indicate.
你是說如果我們
Are you telling me that if we
發表波士頓有五十個戀童癖神父的報道
run a story with 50 pedophile priests in Boston--
麥克
Mike.
我們就會陷入跟你報道波特案後一樣的激烈爭論
We'll get into the same catfight you got into on Porter,
除了製造噪音之外完全沒有改變任何事情
which made a lot of noise but changed things not one bit.
我們得把注意力集中在教會機構 而不是個別神父
We need to focus on the institution, not the individual priests.
慣例跟政策
Practice and policy.
你們得讓我看到教會操縱了司法體系
Show me the church manipulated the system
所以這些傢伙才得以逃脫指控
so that these guys wouldn't have to face charges.
要讓我看到他們一次又一次地
Show me they put those same priests back into parishes
把同一批神父塞回教區
time and time again.
讓我看到這是一個體系的 從上而下的
Show me this was systemic, that it came from the top down.
聽起來我們是要對付勞啊
Sounds like we're going after law.
我們是要追查這個體系
We're going after the system.
列一張我們目前掌握的所有受害人的清單 開始行動吧
Make a list of all the victims we have. Start reaching out.
-如果需要幫助可以把馬特請來 -嗯哼 好的
- And bring Matt in if you need help. - Mm-hmm. Okay.
-嘿 你什麼時候去斯普林菲爾德 -我們的聽證會是在週一
- Hey, when do you go to Springfield? - Our hearing is Monday.
好的
Okay.
喂 羅比 你有時間嗎
Hey, robby, you got a second?
有的
Yeah.
我 離我家一個街區的地方
I, uh-- I got one of those
有個治療中心
treatment centers a block from my house.
周圍的鄰居都有小孩
We got neighbors with kids.
我知道我們的工作是機密
I know that the work we do is confidential,
但我覺得 我應該告訴他們
but I'm feeling like... I should tell 'em.
我們很快就會告訴他們了
We'll tell 'em soon.
你確定
You sure?
-對 -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
嗨 我是薩夏·法伊弗 《波士頓環球報》的
Hi there. I'm sacha pfeiffer. I'm with the Boston globe.
我正在找一位名為馬修·沃爾什的先生
I'm just looking for a gentleman by the name of Matthew Walsh.
呃 不 他不是
Uh, no, he's not.
-就在那邊 -好的 好
- Right there. - Yeah. Okay. Okay.
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
我是《波士頓環球報》的薩夏·法伊弗
I'm sacha pfeiffer from the Boston globe.
-哦 你有什麼事 -我想跟托馬斯·肯尼迪談談
- Yeah, what do you want? - I'd like to speak with Thomas Kennedy.
-他已經不住這裏了 -那你知道他住哪嗎
- He doesn't live here anymore. - Do you know where he lives?
先生 我只是想問幾個
Sir, I'd just like to ask a few--
我是薩夏·法伊弗 《波士頓環球報》的
sacha pfeiffer, Boston globe.
-噢 是 你好 -你好 謝謝
- Oh, yeah. Hi. - Hi. Thank you.
-你還能想到什麼其他事嗎 -沒了
- Anything else you can recall? - No.
想不起了 不過我有個堂姐在昆西
No, but I got a cousin in Quincy.
她幾年後在街上見過他
She saw him in the street a few years later.
主教走進了房子
The bishop came to the house.
他說之前從沒發生過這樣的事情
He said nothing like this had ever happened before.
他叫我們不要起訴
He asked us not to press charges.
那你母親是怎麼做的
And what did your mother do?
我母親
My mother?
她居然還拿出了餅乾招待
She put out freakin' cookies.
當時有很大的壓力讓我們保持沉默
There was a lot of pressure to keep quiet.
-來自教會的壓力嗎 -對 來自教會的
- From the church? - Yeah, from the church.
但不只是教會
But not just the church.
還有我的朋友
From my friends.
其他的教區居民
From the other parishioners.
嗯 我治療的很多神父
Well, many of the priests that I treated
都是性心理發育不良
were psychosexually stunted.
情感方面還停留在十二三歲的水平
On the emotional level of a 12- or 13-year-old.
天啊
Jesus.
首領主教當然知道 每個人都知道
Sure the chief knew. Everybody knew.
但沒有人想給神父戴上手銬
But nobody wants to cuff a priest.
嗯 那公訴人呢
Mmm. And what about the prosecutor?
-我不該談這件破事 -其實我覺得你應該
- I shouldn't talk about this shit. - I think you should, actually.
你認識赫爾利神父或者蓋爾神父嗎
Do you know a father Hurley or a father Gale?
認識
I do.
-我會把你打得屁滾尿流 -抱歉打擾你了
- I'll beat the shit out of you. - Sorry to bother you.
你不要再來了 不要再來
You leave me alone. You leave
打擾我兄弟 聽到了嗎 該死的
my brother alone. You hear me? Goddamn it.
你好 我找羅納德·帕奎因
Hi there. I'm looking for Ronald paquin.
怎麼了
Yes?
-你就是帕奎因神父嗎 -是的 沒錯
- You're father paquin? - Yes. That's right.
我是《波士頓環球報》的薩夏·法伊弗 我
I'm sacha pfeiffer from the Boston globe. I--
-好的 -我能問你幾個問題嗎
- okay. - Could I ask you a few questions?
問吧 親愛的
Go ahead, dear.
我們跟幾個小時候在黑弗裏爾的聖約翰浸信會
We spoke to several men who knew you when they were boys
就認識你的人談過
at St. John the baptist in haverhill.
他們說你曾性騷擾過他們 這是真的嗎
Did-- they told us you molested them. Is that true?
嗯 當然 我胡鬧過
Mmm, sure, I fooled around.
但我自己從未感到開心過
But I never felt gratified myself.
這樣 嗯
Right. Um--
但你承認在聖約翰浸信會性騷擾過男孩子們
but you admit to molesting boys at St. John the baptist?
對對 但就像我說的 我從來沒得到過任何快感
Yes, yes, but as I said, I never got any pleasure from it.
瞭解這一點是很重要的
That's important to understand.
好的
Right.
嗯 但你能告訴我
Um, but can you tell me
你是在哪裏 又是怎麼玩弄那些男孩子的
where and how you fooled around with these boys?
我要說清楚一點 我從來沒有強暴過任何人
I want to be clear. I never raped anyone.
這是不一樣的 我是知道的
There's a difference. I should know.
-你怎麼知道的 -我就被強暴過
- How would you know? - I was raped.
我很抱歉 是誰強暴了你
I'm sorry. Who raped you?
-羅尼 你在跟誰講話 -沒事的 簡
- Ronny, who are you talking to? - It's okay, Jane.
-帕奎因神父 誰強暴了你 -你是誰
- Father paquin, who raped you? - Who are you?
呃 我是薩夏·法伊弗 《環球報》的
Uh, sacha pfeiffer, from the globe.
-請離開我的走廊 -我能自己說話
- Please get off my porch. - I can speak for myself.
-回房去 羅恩 -先生
- Get inside the house, Ron. - Mr.--
-進去 羅恩 -好吧
- get inside, Ron. - Okay.
-抱歉 您是 -我是他妹妹
- I'm sorry. Who are you? - I'm his sister.
-並且我希望你不要再回來這裏了 -帕奎因小姐
- And I don't want you coming back here. - Miss paquin--
我會在街尾超過你的
beat you to the end of the street.
-不可能 -我上次就超過你了
- No, you won't. - I beat you last time.
才沒有 你作弊了
No, you didn't. You cheated. You did.
能請你為我闡明一下《環球報》的態度嗎 阿爾巴諾先生
Could you please clarify the globe's position for me, Mr. Albano?
好的 斯威尼法官
Yes, judge sweeney.
我們關於公開這些文件的論證
Our argument to make these documents public
主要是基於第一修正案的
rests mainly on first amendment grounds.
我們還有一些其他相關的論證
We also have a number of other relevant arguments.
法官閣下 畢竟這是個自由裁量指令
After all, your honor, this was a discretionary order.
是的 它取決於法官的裁量
Yes. It was made at the judge's discretion.
嘿 麥克
Hey, Mike.
嗨 喬
Hey, Joe.
聚焦的記者來到斯普林菲爾德做什麼
What's a spotlight reporter doing in Springfield?
你的阿爾巴諾正在逆水行舟
Your boy albano's sledding uphill.
你真的覺得你們有機會贏這場官司嗎
You actually think you have a shot at winning this thing?
你想讓我對《先驅報》發表評論嗎
You want me to comment for the herald?
「環球報記者不予置評
"Globe reporter would not comment,
但他看起來不抱希望」
but he did not seem hopeful."
他完全不試圖隱瞞
He didn't try and hide it at all.
他有相當奇怪的合理化說法
He had this really odd rationalization for it,
好像玩弄小男孩是完全正常的事情
like it was totally normal to fool around with little boys.
我真的很想回去 我覺得他會願意跟我們談談
I'd really like to go back. I think he'd talk to us.
噢 我們會的
Oh, we will.
只是時機未到
Just not yet.
我希望你現在繼續重點關注受害者們
I want you to stay focused on the victims right now.
薩夏 他們把塔爾伯特神父送到哪了
Sacha, where'd they send father Talbot again?
呃 好像是 捨沃羅斯
Um, I think-- wasn't that cheverus?
捨沃羅斯 沒錯 等等
Cheverus. That's right. Wait.
塔爾伯特是波士頓天主教高中的嗎
Father Talbot from bc high?
對 你認識他嗎
Yeah. You know him?
嗯 我們是同一時期讀的中學
Yeah. He was there when I was.
-是受害者嗎 -對 住在普羅維登斯
- We have a victim? - Yeah. Lives in Providence.
這些文件都無關個人 法官閣下
There's nothing personal in these documents, your honor.
他們是關於紅衣主教怎麼處理
They concern how the cardinal is handling--
請說「總教區」
say "The archdiocese."
什麼
Excuse me?
你不能把所有事都歸為紅衣主教的所為 阿爾巴諾先生
You don't get to tag the cardinal with everything, Mr. Albano.
請說「總教區」
Say "The archdiocese."
斯威尼法官 《環球報》不是
Judge sweeney, the globe is not a
本案相關的任何一方 他們只是想增加銷量罷了
party to this case. They just want to sell papers.
如果加拉貝迪安先生沒有詆毀主教的清名
If Mr. Garabedian had not smeared the cardinal's good name,
我們也不會在這裏了
we wouldn't even be here.
法官閣下 我反對使用「詆毀」這個詞
Your honor, I object to the use of the word "Smear."
-已悉 加拉貝迪安先生 -謝謝 法官閣下
- Duly noted, Mr. Garabedian. - Thank you, your honor.
-還有嗎 羅傑斯先生 -沒了 法官閣下
- Anything else, Mr. Rogers? - No, your honor.
阿爾巴諾先生 您請繼續
Mr. Albano, you may continue.
《環球報》認為
The globe believes having--
喂 米奇 最近好嗎
hey, Mitch, how you doing?
挺好的
I'm fine.
他挺難搞的啊 那個威爾遜·羅傑斯
He's tough, that Wilson Rogers.
他太自以為是 還很馬虎
He's smug. And he's sloppy.
看起來不馬虎啊
He doesn't seem sloppy.
你沒有我知道的多 相信我
You don't know the half of it. Trust me.
你還知道什麼
What's the half of it?
告訴我啊 米奇
Tell me the half of it, Mitch.
-私底下講嗎 -對 偷偷告訴我
- Off the record? - Off the record, yeah.
三年前 我接到一個前神父的電話
Three years ago, I get a call from an ex-priest.
安東尼·本澤維奇
Anthony benzevich.
他在62年的聖餐禮上
He was at blessed sacrament back in '62,
看到吉歐根
and he saw geoghan...
把小男孩們帶進管區臥室
Taking little boys up to the rectory bedroom, okay?
他覺得很震驚 然後就告訴了主教
So he's appalled, all right? Tells the bishop about it.
然後主教威脅要把他派到南美
And the bishop threatens to reassign him to south America.
-老天 -對 沒錯
- Jesus. - Yeah, all right.
所以快進三十五年 本澤維奇在報上看到
So fast-forward 35 years, benzevich reads
吉歐根被指控對數百個孩子進行過性騷擾
that geoghan has been charged with molesting hundreds of kids.
然後他感到內疚 給我打了電話
All right? So he feels guilty. He calls me.
所以你手裏有一份神父
So you have testimony of a priest
在62年向他上級舉報吉歐根的證詞嗎
telling his superiors about geoghan in '62?
不 我沒有
No, I do not.
因為我讓本澤維奇來做宣誓證詞的時候
Because when I called benzevich in to give a deposition,
他帶了個律師過來
he comes in with a lawyer.
-威爾遜·羅傑斯 -對
- Wilson Rogers. - Right.
然後本澤維奇神父就突然變得記憶模糊了
And suddenly father benzevich has a very foggy memory.
什麼也不記得了 沒用了
Can't remember anything. He's useless.
所以我就回去工作 忘了這件事
So I go back to work. I forget about it. Whatever.
直到一年前 我找到一篇文章
Until about a year ago, I find an article
是講有一個神父警告教會注意吉歐根的事
about a priest who warned church officials about geoghan.
-本澤維奇去找了媒體嗎 -對
- Benzevich went to the press? - Yeah.
對 當地報紙 叫做《愛國者紀事報》 沒人看到
Yeah. Local paper, patriot ledger. Nobody saw it.
但我有本澤維奇的公開聲明了
But now I got benzevich on record.
所以我提出動議讓本澤維奇再次宣誓作證
So I file a motion to depose benzevich a second time. All right?
然後威爾遜·羅傑斯 那個自以為是的王八蛋
And Wilson Rogers, that smug son of a bitch,
他提了個動議來反對我的動議
he files a motion opposing my motion.
就是那時候我抓住了他的把柄
And that's when I have him.
把柄 什麼把柄
Have-- have him how?
羅傑斯反對我的動議 所以我得做個論證
Rogers opposes my motion, so I have to make an argument
證明為什麼要允許
as to why I'm allowed to
我再次請本澤維奇神父作證
depose father benzevich a second time, okay?
但是這次 我可以附加上一些證據
But this time, I'm allowed to attach exhibits.
你明白我在說什麼嗎
Do you follow what I'm saying?
-附加上那些密封文件嗎 -對
- The sealed documents? - Yes.
我可以附上
I can attach the sealed documents
我發現的密封文件 雷贊德斯先生
that I've gotten in discovery, Mr. Rezendes,
就是你們報社現在在找的那些文件
the same documents that your paper is currently suing for.
你在唬我
You're shitting me.
什麼 不不 我沒騙你
What? No. No, I'm not shitting you.
所以我調出十四份最確鑿的文件
So I pull out the 14 most damning docs
把它們附加到我的動議裏
and I attach them to my motion.
這樣就能證明了一切 一切
And they prove everything. Everything.
關於教會 關於主教 關於勞
About the church, about the bishops, about Law.
而這是全部公開的嗎
And it's all public?
因為你反對羅傑動議的動議
Because your motion to oppose Roger's motion--
是公開的
is public.
對 就是這樣 現在你終於注意到了
Yeah. Exactly. Now you're paying attention.
所以我現在能直接走進法院
So I could just walk into that
拿到那些文件嗎
courthouse right now and get those documents?
不 不行 因為那些文件不在法院
No, you cannot, because the documents are not there.
但你剛才說它們是公開的
But you just said they're public.
我是說過 但這裏是波士頓
I know I did. But this is Boston.
而教會並不希望有人找到它們
And the church does not want them to be found.
所以它們不在那裏
So they are not there.
米奇 你是說天主教會
Mitch, are you telling me that the catholic church
能從法院移走法律文件嗎
removed legal documents from that courthouse?
聽著 我沒瘋 也沒得妄想癥
Look, I'm not crazy. I'm not paranoid.
我是有處世經驗的人
I'm experienced.
查查檔案記事表 你就明白了
Check the docket. You'll see.
他們什麼都能操縱
They control everything.
什麼都能
Everything.
我得回去了
I gotta go back in.
我得趕緊去拿那些該死的文件
I just got the fucking documents.
訴訟事件表流水號49 吉歐根案
Docket entry number 49, in the geoghan case.
-好的 謝謝 -我們十分鐘後關門
- Okay, thanks. - We close in 10 minutes.
十分鐘 好的
Ten minutes? All right.
羅比
Robby.
嘿 你絕對不會相信
Hey. You're not gonna believe it.
加拉貝迪安給了我一個提示
Garabedian gave me a tip.
有一些密封文件已經公開了
Some of the sealed docs are already public.
它們是他申請的動議的一部分
They're part of a motion he filed.
他說它們是文件中的精華
He said they're the best of the bunch.
我們不必等斯威尼的裁決了
We don't have to wait for sweeney's ruling.
-所以我們能搞到它們嗎 -對 但它們不在那裏
- So we can get them? - Yeah, but they're not there.
已經跟阿爾巴諾談過了
Already talked to albano.
他說我們要做的就是提出動議
He said all we have to do is file a motion,
斯威尼就會讓米奇重新歸檔那些文件
and sweeney will order Mitch to refile the docs.
你覺得那些文件是
And you think these documents are--
他說那十四份文件正是我們需要的 非常重要
he said these 14 docs are all we need. They're huge.
好吧
Okay.
我會打給本 做得很好
I'll call Ben. Good work.
這是純粹的意外
Is this purely an accident
還是有意的行為
or could this have been an intentional act?
無論如何 這座建築都受到了重大的損壞
Either way, extensive damage has been done to this building.
怎麼回事
What happened?
他們說是一架支持機 但那根本不是
They're saying it's a prop plane, but that's not a prop plane.
叫琳達馬上把在這兒的所有記者都召集過來
Tell Linda to get every reporter we have in here now.
我們要為受害者祈禱
You pray for the victims.
要為傷者祈禱
You pray for the injured.
要為倖存者祈禱
And you pray for those who survived.
還要為這個國家祈禱
You pray, too, for the nation.
希望我們對此的回應
That our response to this
能反映出我國最崇高的理想
might reflect the best ideals of our nation.
甚至能反映出上帝的教義
And even more, reflect god's own teaching,
不僅表現在基督教和猶太教
not only as it's shown in christianity and judaism
還有伊斯蘭教
but in islam as well.
-說的不錯 誰在那裏 -保爾森
- Not bad. Who's there? - Paulson.
等他回來後我想跟他談談
I wanna talk to him when he's back.
雷贊德斯找到方法去佛羅里達了嗎
Did rezendes find a way to get to Florida yet?
他們剛開放了普羅維登斯的機場
They just opened the airport in Providence.
他正在過去的路上
He's on his way there now.
本 我需要多點人在港務局
Ben, I'm gonna need more people on massport.
我會派給你三個人
I'll give you three of my guys.
-羅比 你的團隊也去負責這事 -收到
- Robby, put your team on that too. - Got it.
-還有 羅比 其他的事都先放到一邊 -明白
- And, robby, everything else stops. - Understood.
麥克為什麼要去佛羅里達
Why is Mike going to Florida?
去航校 那是他們學開飛機的地方
Flight school. It's where they learned to fly.
羅比 我這周安排了好多受害者要採訪
Robby, I've got a lot of victim interviews set up this week.
你得取消了
You're gonna have to cancel 'em.
-這會很艱難 -我知道 簡直瘋了
- That's gonna be hard. - I know. This is nuts.
兩天前我跟我老婆說我們
Two days ago I told my wife we
會報道一起全世界最爆炸性的新聞
gotta be working the biggest story on the planet.
《波士頓環球報》
Boston globe.
《波士頓環球報》 請稍等
Boston globe. One moment, please.
是的 如果您有什麼消息 我會幫您轉到《都市報》
Yes, if you have a tip, I will transfer you down to Metro.
我是米切爾·加拉貝迪安
Mitchell garabedian.
米奇 我是麥克 我一直想聯繫你
Mitch, it's Mike. I've been trying to reach you.
我沒有時間和你說話 雷贊德斯先生
I don't have time to talk to you, Mr. Rezendes.
很快就好 你重新歸檔那些文件了嗎
Hey, just quickly. Did you refile those docs yet?
沒有 我剛接到傳令 還需要點時間
No. I just got the order. It takes time.
-好的 很好 你能拖延一下歸檔時間嗎 -為什麼
- Okay, great. Can you hold off on refiling them? - Hold off?
我得去一趟佛羅里達 你一歸檔它們就公開了
I have to go to Florida. Once you refile they're public.
其他報紙也能得到它們
Other newspapers will be able to get a hold of 'em.
其他報紙什麼的我不關心
Other newspapers are not my concern.
我收到了裁決令
I received a judicial order.
我跟你說了教會正盯著我
I told you the church is watching me.
喂 米奇 拜託你 我只需要幾周時間
Hey, Mitch, please. All I need is a few more weeks.
我不敢保證 再見
I can't make any promises. Good-bye.
米奇 米奇 媽的
Mitch! Mitch! Shit!
靠
Shit.
聽著 我算是明白了
Look, I get it.
沒人想看到關於
No one wants to read about
兒童被神父強暴的新聞 尤其是現在
kids getting raped by priests, especially now.
但你讓那麼多人
But you asked a lot of people
回憶了一些非常痛苦的經歷 然後就消失了
to relive some very painful experiences, and you just disappear.
菲爾 你知道我們為什麼得暫停這個報道
Phil, you know why we were taken off of this story.
九·一一都過去六個星期了
It's been six weeks since 9/11.
我知道 我們會重新追蹤這件事的
I realize that, and we're gonna get back to it.
什麼時候
When?
-你們還是會跟上次一樣 -不是的
- You're doing the same thing you guys did last time. - No.
-你們準備放棄了 -不會的
- You're dropping us. - No.
也許我該把這件事告訴《先驅報》
Maybe I should tell the herald that story.
好吧 菲爾 你去吧
Okay, Phil, you go ahead and do that.
這樣我們目前的成果全都會付之一炬 但我阻止不了你
It'll undo all the work we've done, but I can't stop you.
聽我說 我會來這裏是因為我在乎
Listen to me. I am here because I care.
我們不會放棄的
We're not going away.
我們會不偏不倚地 把這件事公諸於眾
We're gonna tell this story. We're gonna tell it right.
我們只是還需要一點時間 這是我們全部的請求
We just need a little more time. That's all we're asking for.
何必請求呢
Why bother asking?
不管怎樣你們都會想幹什麼就幹什麼
You're gonna do what you want anyway.
你們總是這樣
You always do.
菲爾
Phil.
Phil!
喂
Hey.
-南海灘怎麼樣 -是博因頓海灘 非常不同的地方
- How's South Beach? - Boynton beach. Remarkably different place.
怎麼了
What's up?
米奇·加拉貝迪安今天聯繫我了
Mitch garabedian called me today.
-他為什麼打給你 -因為知道你會吼他
- Why'd he call you? - 'Cause he knew you'd yell at him.
-他重新歸檔了那些文件 -什麼
- He refiled the docs. - What?
羅比 那些文件現在是公開的了
Robby, those docs are public now.
我們得在別人之前趕過去
We gotta get there before anyone else does.
我知道 我知道 我知道
I know. I know. I know.
趕緊把手頭上的事結束掉 去趕最早的航班
Just wrap up whatever you're doing and get the first flight out.
我現在就訂票
I'll book a flight now
明天直接去法院
and go straight to the courthouse tomorrow.
-好的 進去之後通知我 -好的
- All right. Call me when you get in. - Okay.
羅比 我想讓菲爾·薩維亞諾知道我們又重新著手這件事了
Robby, I'd like to let Phil saviano know that we're back on it.
好主意
Good idea.
跟漢西吃晚飯去吧 這可能會是很長時間以來的最後一次了
Go have dinner with Hansi. Might be the last time for a while.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
羅比 我們見過麥克利什之後
Robby, after we saw macleish,
我就開始重新看那些剪報
I started going back through the clips.
上周終於有了點時間
And I had a little time last week finally.
所以 嗯 我找到了這個
So, um, I found that.
這是93年的
It's from '93.
SSK字幕組
波特案受害者的律師稱同地區
還有其他20位神父受到起訴
就這個嗎
That it?
對對 就 就這個
Yeah. Yeah, that's-- that's it.
晚安
Good night.
好的 晚安
Okay. Good night.
你好
Hello.
所以 我大概比您小幾歲 是嗎
So, I was probably a few years after you, right?
不 你比我小多了
No, you were more than a few.
相信我
Believe me.
嗯 離開波士頓天主教高中之後 我去了普羅維登斯
Well, after bc high, I came down to Providence
為修道士們打曲棍球
and played hockey for the friars.
哦 你一定表現得很不錯
Oh, well, you must have been pretty good.
不不 這水平在大學裏就只能坐冷板凳
No. Rode the bench in college. Yeah.
但我愛這座城市
But I loved the city.
啊哈 而且我們剛剛有了第三個孩子
Uh-huh. And we just had our third kid.
而且提醒你一下 我還在看《環球報》
And I still get my globe, for the record.
啊 那很好 挺好的
Ah, that's good to know. Good to know.
聽著 凱文 呃 其實我來這裏的原因
Look, Kevin, uh, that's actually why I'm here.
-嗯 -我
- Yeah? - I...
我想問你幾個關於塔爾伯特神父的問題
I need to ask you some questions about father Talbot.
你怎麼發現的
How'd you find out?
這個 呃
Well-- um--
我想這個應該不重要了
I guess it doesn't matter.
呵 我連我老婆都沒說過
Hell, I never even told my wife.
借過
Excuse me.
嘿 嘿 嘿 我得進去
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. I need to get in there.
-我們關門了 -拜託 讓我進去 五分鐘就好
- We're closed. - Come on. Let me in. Five minutes.
-抱歉 我們關門了 -拜託 五分鐘就好
- I'm sorry. We're closed. - Come on. Five minutes.
給 好了
Here. There.
-這是關於吉歐根案的嗎 -沒錯
- This is the geoghan case? - That's right.
-那些文件是密封的 -不 現在有個公開的動議
- Those records are sealed. - No. That's a public motion.
那些文件現在是公開的
Those records are public.
-我是《環球報》的 -挺行的啊
- Look, I work for the globe. - Good for you.
-我可以跟你的主管談談嗎 -他今天不在
- Can I talk to your supervisor? - He's not in today.
那法官呢
What about a judge? There
一定有法官在處理這類事情的
must be judges that work on this kind of thing.
在六樓
Sixth floor.
我們明白對塔爾伯特神父的
We understand the nature
指控到底是怎麼一回事
of the allegations against father Talbot.
我只是不知道你們想從科莫扎校長身上問出些什麼
I'm just not sure what you want from president kemeza.
比爾接手的時候塔爾伯特已經離開很久了
Talbot taught here long before bill took over.
嗯 當然
Mmm. Of course.
我們只是想知道是不是
We just want to know if it's possible
包括校長 教職人員 董事會在內
that the president, the faculty, the board,
都沒人知道那時候發生了什麼
that no one knew what was going on at the time.
我1979年畢業的
I graduated in 1979,
但我完全不知道有這些事
and I had no idea about any of this.
所以如果你是在暗示吉本斯神父和
So if you're suggesting that father Gibbons
卡拉漢神父有任何方面的
and father Callahan had in any way--
吉本斯和卡拉漢
Gibbons and Callahan.
我是說 他們像管海軍一樣管理這個地方
I mean, they ran this place like the Navy.
你真的覺得他們不知道嗎
You really think they didn't know?
這間學校大得很 羅比 你知道的
It's a big school, robby. You know that.
現在我們說的是七個所謂的
And then we're talking about
受害者 還是差不多八年前的事嗎
seven alleged victims over, what, eight years?
不 我們現在知道的有七個
No, we're talking about, you know, seven that we know about.
太荒謬了
This is ridiculous.
-你們是在這裏挖新聞 -傑克 傑克
- You're reaching for a story here-- - Jack. Jack.
傑克 如果我是那時候的校長 我會知道的
Jack. If I had been president then, I would've known.
比爾 我不確定這有沒有關係
Bill, I'm not sure that's relevant.
不然你覺得他們為什麼把塔爾伯特送到捨沃羅斯
Why do you think they sent Talbot up to cheverus?
你知道他們想讓他離開這裏
You know they wanted him out of town.
羅比
Robby,
就像比爾所說的 出於好意
as well intentioned as bill's remarks are,
我希望在達成共識之前
I'm hoping we can keep this
這件事能先保密
between us until we all get on the same page.
這就是我們來這裏的原因嗎 達成共識
Is that why we're here, to get on the same page?
不 我們來這裏是因為你是
No, we're here because you're
一名重要的校友 羅比 也是朋友
an important alumnus, robby, and a friend.
正是 而且我們知道你跟我們一樣關心這所學校
Exactly. And we know you care about this school as much as we do.
你在這裏參加過體育運動嗎 傑克
Did you play a sport here, Jack?
嗯 足球 怎麼了
Yeah. Football. Why?
嗯 我參加的是田徑
Mmm. I ran track.
我昨天去普羅維登斯
You know, I went to Providence yesterday
跟塔爾伯特神父的受害者談過
to talk to one of father Talbot's victims.
他在這裏打曲棍球 而且打得不錯
He played hockey here. And he's one of the better ones.
他娶了老婆 有孩子 事業有成
He's got a wife, kids, good job.
在大概十分鐘的深入談話之後
About 10 minutes into the conversation,
他失控了
the guy breaks down.
哭個不停
You know, couldn't stop crying.
說他一直想不通塔爾伯特神父為什麼會選中他
Said he could never figure out why father Talbot picked him.
塔爾伯特神父是曲棍球隊的教練
Father Talbot coached the hockey team.
所以
So...
我想我們比較幸運
I guess we just got lucky.
你跟我都是
You and me.
傑克·鄧恩在這學校工作嗎
Does Jack Dunn work for the school?
沒有 他是波士頓大學的公關
No, he's PR for Boston college.
他們需要幫助的時候就會找他
They call him when they need help.
那皮特·康利呢 他為什麼在這兒
And Pete conley, why was he there?
問得好 皮特是位重要校友
Good question. Pete's a big alum.
但我直接聯繫比爾 請求坐下來詳談的
But I called bill directly and I asked for a sit-down.
我沒提到過其他任何人
I never mentioned anybody else.
好像每個人都已經知道這件事了
It's like everybody already knows the story.
-對 除了我們 -而我們就在那裏工作
- Yeah. Except us. - And we work right there.
-沃爾泰拉法官 -是的
- Judge volterra? - Yes?
你好 我是《波士頓環球報》的記者麥克·雷贊德斯
Hi. I'm Mike Rezendes from the Boston Globe.
我想查閱資料室的
I'm having some trouble accessing
一些公開材料 但遇到了點困難
some public records down in the records room.
我能否與你談談
I was wondering if I could have a word with you?
-好的  -謝謝
-All right. -Thank you.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
我得跟你說 雷贊德斯先生
These exhibits you're after, Mr. Rezendes,
這些材料可是敏感的很
they're very sensitive records.
無意冒犯 法官先生 但這不是問題所在
With all due respect, your honor, that's not the question.
這些材料是公開的
The records are public.
也許吧 那你跟我講講
Maybe so, but tell me,
新聞記者有什麼責任
where's the editorial responsibility
把這些記錄公諸於眾呢
in publishing records of this nature?
那新聞記者又有什麼責任
Well, where's the editorial
不把這些記錄公諸於眾呢
responsibility in not publishing them?
你不能把這帶走 你得去複印一份
You can't take those. You need to make copies.
-我這就去複印室  -那裏四點鐘就關門了
-I'm going to the copy room. -It closed at 4:00.
聽著 我給你
Look, I'll give you...
八十三塊 借用你的複印機
83 bucks to use yours.
嘿 出租車
Hey! Cabbie!
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
到莫裏西大道的波士頓環球報大樓
Take me to the Boston Globe on morrissey boulevard.
別走九十三大道 走多切斯特大道
Don't take 93. Take Dorchester Avenue.
羅比 這太不可思議了
Robby, it's incredible.
勞早就知道吉歐根的事了 這點毫無疑問
Law knew about Geoghan for years, no question.
有一名叫做瑪格麗特·加蘭特的女士給勞寄過一封信
There's a letter to law from a woman, Margaret Gallant,
她在上世紀八十年代初
who lived in Jamaica Plain
居住在牙買加平原 那時吉歐根是那裏的神父
in the early '80s when geoghan was there.
聽聽這個
Listen to this.
「教會是我們家庭的根
"Our family is rooted in the church.
哪怕身處痛苦之中 我們也竭力
Our desire is to protect the holy orders
維護著聖職
even in the midst of our agony
隱瞞了家族中七個男孩被侵犯的事實」
over the seven boys in our family who have been violated."
七個啊 羅比 七個男孩
Seven, robby. Seven boys.
「我們被迫保持沉默
"It was suggested we keep silent.
我們從未質疑過教會的權威
We did not question the authority of the church two years ago.
直到兩年前 我得知神父吉歐根還在他的教區任職」
But since Father Geoghan is still in his parish--"
她把這封信寄給了勞 卻完全被無視了
but she sent it to law and law did shit.
這兒還有一封寄給勞的信 同一年的 聽著
Here's another one to law, same year. Listen to this.
「針對最近教會將神父吉歐根委派至
"A word on the recent assignment of father Geoghan...
韋斯頓的聖朱麗亞教區一事 我有話要說
As an associate at St. Julia's in Weston.
神父吉歐根曾有過
Father Geoghan has a history
性侵男童的記錄
of homosexual involvement with young boys.
我想他最近被調離聖布蘭登教區
I understand his recent departure from St. Brendan's
也與此有關
may be related to this problem.
我能否請求教區
I wonder if Father Geoghan
撤銷對其的降職處理
should not be reduced to just weekend work
而讓他接受治療
while receiving some kind of therapy.
對於您長期以來的關懷我感激不盡
You know how grateful I am to you for your constant concern.
願主保佑您
Sincerely yours in our lord,
尊敬的主教大人約翰·M·達西 波士頓副主教上
most reverend John M D'arcy, auxiliary bishop of Boston.
一九八四年十二月七日」
December 7, 1984."
這是一個副主教寫的信嗎
An auxiliary bishop wrote that?
這太令人震驚了
That's incredible.
他越級了 我是說 加蘭特是什麼時候寫的信
He broke ranks. I mean, when did Gallant write her letter?
1984年 勞直接無視了
1984. And law just ignored it.
這樣的信怎麼能無視呢
How do you ignore that freakin' letter?
但我們拿到了
We got 'em.
看了這些信 我們不能想別的了 這是證據啊
You can't read these letters and think anything else. It's proof.
是啊 沒錯
Yeah, it is.
這很好
This is good work.
我們要不要把它交給本
Should we take it up to Ben?
呃 不 暫時不要
Uh, no. Not yet.
為什麼不呢 我們抓到勞的把柄了 這就是啊
Why not? We got law. This is it.
不 這只是勞包庇一個神父的證據
No, this is law covering for one priest.
還有其他九十位神父逍遙法外呢
There's another 90 out there.
我知道 等我們拿到證據了再曝光他們也不遲
Yeah, we'll print that story when we get it,
但我們現在得把這個報道出來
but we gotta go with this now.
這個報道我不想倉促而行 麥克
I'm not gonna rush this story,Mike.
我們別無選擇 羅比
We don't have a choice, Robby.
如果我們不趕緊報道
If we don't rush to print,
就會有人
somebody else is going
發現這些信件 搶先披露出來
to find these letters and butcher the story.
《先驅報》的喬·昆比當時就在法院蹲點呢
Joe Quimby from The Herald was at the freaking courthouse.
那我們就先寫一份報道放著
So we'll write a holding
同時緊盯《先驅報》的動向
story and we'll keep our eye on The Herald.
緊盯《先驅報》的動向
Keep our eye on The Herald?
如果他們插手進來 報道出了差錯的話 教會會把這事給壓下去的
They run this and get it wrong, the church will bury it.
-我們現在就得報道出來 -麥克 麥克
- We gotta do this now. - Mike, Mike.
怎麼了 為什麼要猶豫不決呢
What? Why are we hesitating?
巴倫讓我們抓勞的把柄 我們抓到了
Baron told us to get law. This is law.
巴倫是讓我們揭露整個系統
Baron told us to get the system.
我們需要著眼全局
We need the full scope.
這是我們了結此事的唯一途徑
That's the only thing that will put an end to this.
那我們把這拿去給本 讓他來做決定
Then let's take it to Ben, let him decide.
到時候我自然會拿給他看 這由我來決定
We'll take it to Ben when I say it's time.
到時候了 羅比 是時候了
It's time, Robby! It's time!
他們早就知道了 卻放任悲劇降臨到孩子們身上
They knew and they let it happen. To kids!
受害者本可能是你 也可能是我
Okay? It could've been you. It could've been me.
可能是我們任何人
It could've been any of us.
我們得揭穿這些卑鄙小人
We gotta nail these scumbags.
我們得讓世人知道沒人能逃脫罪責
We gotta show people that nobody can get away with this.
神父不可以 紅衣主教不可以 教皇也不可以
Not a priest or a cardinal or a freaking pope!
你說完了嗎
You finished?
對 我說完了 你簡直就是在放屁
Yeah, I am. This is bullshit.
你沒事吧
You okay?
嗯
Mmm.
你好 漢西
Hey, hansi.
今天工作不順吧 麥克
Hard day at work, Mike?
-給 -謝謝
- Here. - Thank you.
我 我 我不知道我為什麼會那麼生氣
I-I-I-I don't know why I got so pissed off.
我覺得羅比錯了
You know, I think Robby's wrong.
其實 你只是
You know, you're just--
你太關心這次報道了 麥克 大家都一樣
you care about the story, Mike. We all do.
-是啊 也許吧 -嗯
- Yeah, I guess. - Hmm.
我已經不再陪我奶奶去教堂了
I stopped going to church with my Nana.
這 這太難熬了 我
It was-- it was too hard. I--
你知道嗎 我坐在那裏
you know, I'd be sitting there,
然後就會想起喬·克勞利或者其他人
and I would start thinking about Joe Crowley or someone else,
然後我 我就會很憤怒
and I just-- I just got so angry.
你有 你有告訴她原因嗎
Did you-- did you tell her why?
她一周要去三次教堂 麥克
She goes to church three times a week, Mike.
這真的使我很惱火
It really pisses me off.
你知道嗎
You know,
當我還是個小孩子的時候 我真的很喜歡去教堂
I actually really liked going to church when I was a little kid.
嗯
Mmm.
-後來為什麼不去了呢 -沒什麼特別的原因
- Why'd you stop? - Typical shit.
但奇怪的是
But the weird thing is...
我感覺
I think I--
我總覺得沒準有一天我會 我會
I think I figured that maybe one day I w-- I w--
我會再回去的
I would actually go back.
我真的 我真的有這個打算的
I was really-- I was holding on to that.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
當我看完那些信 然後
I read those letters, and it--
就好像是 心裏有什麼東西裂開了
and something just... cracked.
-這感覺很糟糕 -是啊
- It's a shitty feeling. - Yeah.
這種感覺很糟糕
It's a shitty feeling.
-看來你今天過得並不順啊 -嘿 皮特
- Looks like a long day. - Hey, Pete.
很抱歉我還得打攪你
I'm sorry to make it longer.
布萊恩
Brian.
沒有人能拒絕和你喝一杯吧 皮特
Has anyone ever said no to a drink with you, Pete?
嗯 當然有啊
Well, sure.
關鍵是得堅持邀請
But the trick is to keep asking.
-為了波士頓  -波士頓
- For Boston. - Boston.
嗯
Mmm.
那麼 嗯 你是為了紅衣主教的事來的嗎
So, um, you here for the cardinal?
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
我可不敢擅自代表紅衣主教 絕對不敢
I wouldn't-- I wouldn't presume to speak for the cardinal, no.
你知道的 這裏有很多人非常尊敬你 羅比
You know, you got a lot of people here who respect you, Robby.
-嗯 -因為你做的事
- Yeah.  - With work you do.
-這讓我挺開心的 -因為你熱愛這個城市
- That's good to know. - It's 'cause you care about this place.
這也是你身為新聞人的原因 這是你的使命
It's why you do what you do. It's who you are.
但你要知道 人們現在需要教會的存在 比任何時候都需要
You know, but people need the church, more than ever right now.
你可以體會得到
You know, you can feel it.
並且紅衣主教 呃
And the cardinal, uh--
你知道的 紅衣主教他 也許不是完人
you know, the cardinal, he might not be perfect.
但我們不能因為幾粒老鼠屎
But we can't throw out all
就否定他的傑出貢獻
the good he's doing over a few bad apples.
我現在跟你提這些
Now, you know, I'm bringing
是因為我知道這都是巴倫的主意
this up to you because I know this is Baron's idea.
這是他要做的事
His agenda.
我得告訴你 我是說 說句實話
I gotta tell ya, I mean, honest to god,
他不像我們這樣熱愛這座城市
I mean, he doesn't care about the city the way we do.
他怎麼可能呢
I mean, how could he?
這就是你們的慣用伎倆 對嗎 皮特
This is how it happens, isn't it, Pete?
怎麼說
What's that?
一個人去威逼利誘另一個人
A guy leans on a guy,
然後忽然間對整座城市的看法都變了
and suddenly the whole town just looks the other way.
羅比 羅比 聽著
Robby. Robby. Look it.
馬蒂·巴倫只是想賺點名氣罷了
Marty Baron is just trying to make his mark.
他只會在這裏呆上幾年 然後就會陞遷離開了
He's gonna be here for a couple of years and he's gonna move on.
就像他在紐約和邁阿密時一樣
Just like he did in New York and Miami.
但是你又能去哪裏呢
Where are you gonna go?
嗯
Hmm?
晚安 羅比 布萊恩
Good night, Robby. Brian.
-嘿 呃 皮特  -什麼事
- Hey, uh, Pete. - Yeah?
呃 當我們真的報道此事時
Uh, when we do run the story,
額 我需要紅衣主教的評論
uh, I'm gonna need a comment from the cardinal.
我們回頭再談 晚安 羅比
We'll talk again later. Good night, Robby.
晚安 皮特
Night, Pete.
我是羅比
Robby.
什麼
What?
真的假的 什麼時候
No shit. When?
好的 好
Okay. Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
怎麼了
What's up?
斯威尼做出了支持我們的裁決
Sweeney ruled in our favor.
她判決將文件開封
She ruled to unseal the documents.
天哪 哈
Geez. Huh.
教會已經提起了上訴
The church has already filed an appeal.
但初審法院對此的判決仍舊有效
But the trial court ruling is generally upheld in these matters.
那我們什麼時候能拿到那些文件
And when would we get the documents?
科恩也許還得花幾周時間來處理
Probably takes Cohen a few weeks to rule.
然後還需要走一個校訂的流程
Then there's a redaction process.
呃 我認為在一月中旬文件就能公佈了
Uh, I'd say they'd be made public mid-January.
-好的 -行了
- Okay. - All right.
-謝謝 約翰  -沒事
- Thanks, John. - You bet.
-你做得很棒  -謝謝
- Nice work. - Thanks.
《都市報》得寫點東西出來 馬蒂
Metro should run something, Marty.
這事我們不能大肆宣傳
We can't run this one big.
為什麼不能 這是一次意義重大的挑戰修正案的勝利啊
Why wouldn't we? It's a major first amendment victory.
更別提你成功讓
Not to mention, you get an
一個愛爾蘭裔天主教法官來對抗教會
Irish catholic judge ruling against the church?
-這可是個了不得的先例啊 -嗯
- That's a hell of a precedent. - Mm-hmm.
我們不能讓《先驅報》深挖此事
We don't want The Herald going deep on this.
為什麼
Why's that?
你得先迴避一下 彼得
You're gonna have to step out, Peter.
我才不迴避呢
I'm not stepping out.
彼得
Peter.
-你是什麼時候 呃  -幾周前
- When did you, uh-- - a couple of weeks ago.
幾周前
A couple of weeks?
-是的  -然後你現在才告訴我們嗎
- Yeah. - And you're telling us now?
這些材料太重要了
These are substantial.
這些材料清楚地表明勞有瀆職行為
They clearly show that law was negligent.
我需要更多時間
I need more time.
-我想接著調查下去  -調查什麼
- I wanna keep digging. - For what?
-這就是事情真相了  -這不是事實的全部
- This is the goddamn story. - It's not the whole story.
這很棘手啊 我們沒剩下多少時間了
Tough shit. We're on a clock now.
即使我們不報道斯威尼的判決結果
Even if we don't run Sweeney's ruling,
其他報社也可能會發現這些信件 搶先報道
another paper could find these letters and fuck the story.
我知道 但如果我們單獨報道這些信件
Agreed. But we run these letters alone,
勞會道歉 說只發生過一次 他可以把真相掩蓋起來
law apologizes, says it's a one-time thing. He can bury it.
怎麼掩蓋 這些信件證明了他知道罪行卻毫無作為
How? These clearly show he knew and did nothing about it.
聽著 我快要把全部七十個神父的醜聞挖到底了
Look, I'm close to stories on 70 priests.
我們把那些全部搞定後 再加上這些信件
We nail that, along with those letters,
就能證明此事不只是勞的過失
this is proof that this is bigger than law.
而且是整個體系的腐壞
It's the whole system.
你有足夠證據證明全部神父的罪過嗎
You have multiple sources confirming all those priests?
-有一部分了 我可以拿到更多 -太冒險了
- On some. I can get more. - Too risky.
如果我們不把他們每個人
If we're not buttoned up on every
挖的底朝天 教會就會挑我們的毛病
single one of them, the church will pick us apart.
我可以為我們爭取到教會那邊的一個證人
I think I can get us someone from the other side of the aisle.
教會內部的人嗎
Somebody inside the church?
是的 一名律師
Yeah. A lawyer.
他願意公開證明嗎
Will he go on the record?
他背景很深 但值得信賴
Deep background. But he's a solid source.
雷贊德斯需要時間來寫報道
Rezendes needs time to write the story.
我們不能在聖誕節披露 尤其是九·一一事件過後
We don't want to drop it at Christmas, not after 9/11.
我們可以在新年後報導
We could run it just after new year's,
趕在他們公佈剩下的文件之前
before they release the rest of the documents.
好的
All right.
告訴卡內洛斯別報道這次裁決了
Tell Canellos to bury the ruling in Metro.
你有六周時間
You got six weeks.
謝謝
Thank you.
告訴麥克在聖誕節前將初稿交給我
Tell Mike I want a draft by Christmas.
我們還需要教堂方面的回應
And we need a response from lake street.
紅衣主教的公關是誰 還是約翰·沃什嗎
Who does PR for the cardinal? Still John Walsh?
不是 是個新人 叫唐娜·莫裏西 之前在TV網任職 她還很年輕
No, somebody new. Donna Morrissey. She came from TV. She's young.
好的 去做一份引述
Good. Get a quote. We
我們得準備點勞的言論 以示公正
need something from law to appear evenhanded.
羅比 下次得提前給我提個醒
Robby, next time give me a goddamn heads-up.
好的
Will do.
距離截止日還有二十一天零四小時
距離截止日還有八天零二小時
你的線人怎麼樣了
快到時候了
本
羅比 真是稀客啊
Robby, what a nice surprise.
快請進
Come on in.
嘿 親愛的 看看是誰來了
Hey, hon, look who I found outside.
凱倫 能讓我們單獨待會兒嗎
Karen, can you give us a minute?
-當然 -見到你很高興 凱倫
- Sure. - Good to see you, Karen.
什麼事
What's up?
我快沒時間了 吉姆
I'm out of time, Jim.
我們已經寫好了七十位神父的醜聞報道
We've got cover-up stories on 70 priests.
但我的上級要求
But the boss isn't gonna run
必須得到你們這邊的證實後才能披露
it unless I get confirmation from your side.
你瘋了嗎
Are you out of your mind?
拜託了 這是我們的城市啊 吉米
Come on. This is our town, Jimmy.
每個人都知道有罪惡在發生 可沒人有所行動
Everybody knew something was going on, and no one did a thing.
-我們必須結束這一切 -不用你來提醒我該做什麼
- We gotta put an end to it. - Don't tell me what I gotta do.
沒錯 我是幫這些卑鄙小人做了辯護 但那是我的職責所在 羅比
Yeah, I helped defend these scumbags, but that's my job, Robby.
我只是在盡職
I was doing my job.
是啊
Yeah.
你跟其他人一樣
You and everyone else.
滾出我的房子
Get out of my house.
嘿
Hey!
你來我家就為了說這些的嗎
You come to my home and lay this shit on me?
你說得對 羅比
You were right, Robby.
每個人都知道有罪惡發生
We all knew something was going on.
那你當時在哪裏呢 你為什麼耽誤了這麼久
So where were you? What took you so long?
我不知道 吉姆
I don't know, Jim.
把名單給我
Give me the list.
拉裏 我們六小時後就要報道了
Larry, we're going to press in six hours.
唐娜·莫裏西幾小時前說
Donna Morrissey said she'd
她會打給我們 轉述勞的聲明
call us with a quote from law hours ago.
-我也以為 -你是什麼時候跟她說的
- That's what I thought. - When did you talk to her?
-好的 好的 拉裏 -好的
- Okay. Okay, Larry. - Yeah.
好 好的 這是個好消息 謝謝你 皮特
Yeah. Yeah, that's good to know. Thanks, Pete.
有什麼新動向嗎
Anything?
康利說唐娜·莫裏西早該打電話過來的
Conley said Donna Morrissey should've called.
他剛離開教堂
He just left lake street.
是啊 拉斯基也是這麼說的
Yeah, Rasky said the same thing.
這太可笑了 你覺得他們還想先下手為強
This is ridiculous. You'd think they want to get ahead of this.
我是說 他們要不提前採取行動才是傻呢
I mean, they'd be idiots not to.
我真想看看他們讀了我們的報道之後的表情
I would love to see their faces when they read this thing.
星期天可是盛大的主顯節呢
You know,Sunday's the feast of the epiphany.
那挺合適的
That seems appropriate.
我是麥克·雷贊德斯
Mike Rezendes.
你好 唐娜
Hey, Donna.
感謝你的來電 是啊
Thanks for calling. Yeah,
如果你有空的話 我想問幾個問題
I just had a few questions if you have a minute.
什麼
What?
-怎麼了  -又有個形容詞使用不當
- What? - Another adjective.
-有什麼消息嗎 -勞剛剛回絕了我們的提問
- Anything? - Law just turned us down.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
我剛和唐娜·莫裏西通完電話
I just got off the phone with Donna Morrissey.
引述如下 「我們連問題是什麼
She said, quote, "We don't even
都沒有興趣知道」 轉述完畢
want to know what the questions are," End quote.
-她真的這樣說嗎 -是的
- She really said that? - Yeah.
嗯 這樣也行
Well, that ought to do it.
「教會對於《環球報》的疑問
"The church had no interest
表示毫無興趣」
in knowing what the globe's questions would be."
把這句話加到重點內容前面 還有別的嗎
Work it in somewhere before the jump. Anything else?
馬特想把信件放到網上
Matt wants to put the letters
以供讀者自行查閱
online so the readers can see for themselves.
我們可以在文章最後附上網址鏈接
We can run the url at the bottom of the article.
-這樣挺方便的 -好的
- It's pretty straightforward. - Okay.
我們還可以把辦公室的專線電話
We also put the spotlight tip
放在文末 方便大家打進來
line at the end of the story so people can call in.
直接打到我們辦公室來
Goes directly to our office.
我和馬特也可以一早就來 以便接電話
Matt and I can go in in the morning in case we get any calls.
嗯 我更擔心接待處的電話
Yeah, I'm more concerned about the phones at reception.
在我們報道了波特案之後
After we ran the Porter case,
電話中心好幾周都忙得不可開交
the message centers were tied up for weeks.
-這是個問題 -糾察員也是個問題
- It's a real problem. - There were picketers too.
大家都很忙
Lots of 'em.
我會跟理查德談安保工作和電話問題的
I'll talk to Richard about the security and the phones.
呃 後續報道要怎樣進行
Uh, how are we coming on the folo story?
嗯 我們把全部七十個神父的報道都搞定了
Well, we've nailed down multiple stories on 70 priests.
-全部七十個嗎  -嗯
- All 70? - Mm-hmm.
而且拿到了羅比線人的證明 我們隨時可以報道了
And with confirmation from Robby's source, we're ready to go.
我們下周內可以寫好初稿
We can have a draft next week.
羅比 那位給你提供消息的人 我們可以重訪嗎
Robby, that source of yours, is it something we could revisit?
可能有點困難
It might be tough.
那他給幾十個下賤的神父
But he has no problem helping
打掩護時就不困難了嗎
the church protect dozens of dirty priests.
-那傢伙可真卑鄙 -他是一名律師 他只是在做他應做的
- Guy's a scumbag. - He's a lawyer. He's doing his job.
-他就是教會僱傭的騙子 -他是在助紂為虐
- He's a shill for the church. - He knew and did nothing.
他本可以早點說出來 也許還能救回幾條命
He could've said something years ago, maybe saved some lives.
那我們呢
What about us?
-這是什麼意思 -我們早就有不少線索了
- What's that supposed to mean? - We had all the pieces.
為什麼沒能早點發掘真相呢
Why didn't we get it sooner?
-我們哪裏有很多線索了 -我們有薩維亞諾
- We didn't have all the pieces. - We had saviano.
巴雷特和吉歐根
We had Barrett. We had Geoghan.
還有地下室裏那些人名錄
We had the directories in the basement.
這樣說吧 我們現在有了結果
You know what? We got it now.
羅比 這個報道需要聚焦小組的努力
Robby, the story needed spotlight.
麥克 這個組1970年就成立了
Mike, spotlight's been around since 1970.
那又怎樣 我們又沒辦法預知未來 沒人可以
So what? We couldn't see the scope of this. No one could.
羅比 這是由一個該死的神父牽扯出來的
Robby, this started with one goddamn priest.
麥克利什幾年前寄來過一封信 檢舉了二十個神父
Macleish sent us a letter on 20 priests years ago.
薩夏找到了剪報
Sacha found the clip.
你開什麼玩笑 二十名神父嗎
You freaking kidding? Twenty priests?
什麼時候
When?
呃 就在波特案之後 93年12月
Uh, just after Porter. December '93.
我們把這事給了《都市報》 沒有進行後續報道
We buried the story in Metro. No folo.
是你嗎
That was you?
你那時是《都市報》的主管
You were Metro.
是的 是我
Yeah. That was me.
我那時剛接管 完全不記得有這回事
I'd just taken over. I don't remember it at all.
但是 沒錯
But yeah.
嗯
Um,
我能不能 呃 說幾句
can I, uh, say something here?
有時候我們很容易就忘記了
Sometimes it's easy to forget
很多時候我們都在黑暗邊緣徘徊
that we spend most of our time stumbling around in the dark.
一旦光明降臨
Suddenly a light gets turned on,
罪人自會接受懲罰
and there's a fair share of blame to go around.
我無法對調任此地之前的事情作過多評論
I can't speak to what happened before I arrived,
但是 呃 你們所有人都為這次的報道貢獻頗多
but, uh, all of you have done some very good reporting here.
這類報道能夠迅速引起讀者
Reporting that I believe is gonna have an immediate
大範圍的關注
and considerable impact on our readers.
於我而言 這就是我們新聞行業的價值所在
For me, this kind of story is why we do this.
我說過
Having said that,
勞主教和天主教社區
cardinal law and the catholic community
肯定會對此事有強烈的反應
are gonna have a very strong response to this.
所以 如果你們需要休息
So if you need a moment,
完全沒問題
you've earned it.
但是 呃
But, uh,
你們週一早上必須到崗
I will need you back here Monday morning,
全力準備 專心工作
focused and ready to do your job.
-走嗎 -好的
- Leaving? - Yeah.
我 呃 剛剛接到了紅衣主教的電話
I, uh, just got a call from the cardinal.
真的嗎 為什麼
Really. Why?
他想親自告訴我 他決定不對此事做任何評論
He wanted to tell me personally that he decided not to comment.
他還說 他願意 呃 增加給我的好處
Yeah. Said he wanted to, uh, extend me that courtesy.
天哪 那傢伙可真有膽量 你是怎麼說的
Jesus, the balls on that guy. What did you say?
我跟他說 他這麼做是錯的
I told him he was making a
而且我們肯定會把這件事報道出來
mistake and that we were gonna run the story.
我們當然要報道這事
Damn right we're gonna run it.
薩夏 能給我倒杯水嗎
Sacha, can I have a drink of water?
好的 沒問題 奶奶 好的
Yeah. Sure, Nana. Yeah.
我能留著這份報紙嗎
Can I keep this?
當然
Sure.
我認為應該先拿給你看看
I thought you should see it first.
謝謝你把它拿給我
Thank you for bringing it by.
現在 我還有幾位委託人的事要處理
Now, I have some clients I have to attend to.
好的
Yeah.
兩個孩子都被侵犯了
Both kids were abused.
牙買加平原 兩周前發生的
Jamaica Plain. Two weeks ago.
繼續 加油吧 雷贊德斯先生
Keep... doing your work, Mr. Rezendes.
-你們好呀 -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
你們好嗎
How are you guys doing?
-很好 謝謝  -很好
- Good, thanks. - Good.
-嘿 -早上好
- Hey. - Good morning.
睡得好嗎
How'd you sleep?
不是很好 你呢
Not very well. You?
-我幾個月沒睡好覺了 -嗯
- I haven't slept well for months. - Mmm.
噢 謝謝 我 呃 我開始寫書了
Oh, thanks. I, uh, actually started writing.
-寫書 -是的 我一直在寫一本書
- Writing? - Yeah, I've been working on a book.
這能轉移我的注意力
Gives me something else to focus on.
-什麼題材的書 -驚悚
- What kind of book? - Horror.
是的
Yeah.
這裏是聚焦小組
Spotlight.
是的
Yeah.
好的 沒問題 能否 呃 告知下你的姓名
Yeah, of course. Can I, uh-- can I get your name, please?
-你知道今天是星期天吧 -反正沒時間打高爾夫了
- You do know it's Sunday, right? - Couldn't get a tee time.
-今天沒有糾察員 -是啊
- No picketers. - Yeah.
可能還在教堂吧
Probably still at church.
你好 琳達 挺安靜的誒
Hey, Linda. It's quiet, huh?
是啊 最輕鬆的一次加班了
Yeah. Easiest overtime I ever made.
電話一次都沒響過
Phone hasn't rung once.
馬蒂把我的兩個手下都調到聚焦小組去了
Marty sent two of mine down to spotlight.
-文章寫得很棒 夥計們 -謝謝
- Great article, guys. - Thank you.
-謝謝 -聚焦小組
- Thanks. - Spotlight?
好的 是的
Okay. Yep.
這裏是聚焦小組 有什麼可以幫您的嗎
Spotlight. Can I help you?
電話已經響了一上午了
Phones have been ringing all morning.
這裏是聚焦小組
Spotlight.
-麥克 能接下那個嗎 -好 好的
- Mike, can you grab that? - Yeah, yeah.
他們幾乎全是受害者 羅比
They're almost all victims, Robby.
-很抱歉讓您久等了 -我是薩夏·法伊弗
- I'm sorry to make you wait. - Sacha Pfeiffer.
抱歉 你能否
I'm sorry-- can you--
是的 你可以來這裏找我
Yes, you can reach me here.
這裏是聚焦小組
This is spotlight.
我能記一下你的名字嗎
Can I get your name?
你之後還有和住在那的人
Did you happen to have any
聯繫嗎
contact with anybody that was there afterward?
你記得當時是哪一年嗎
Do you remember what year this was?
是哪個教區呢
Which parish was it?
這裏是聚焦小組
This is spotlight.
在2002年 聚焦小組披露了將近600起此類醜聞
在波士頓總教區內有249位神父和兄弟會成員被公開指控性騷擾
波士頓的倖存者預計超過1000人
2002年12月 勞紅衣主教從波士頓總教區辭職
他被重新任命去羅馬的聖母瑪利亞大教堂任職
那是全世界最高級的羅馬天主教教堂之一
重大的醜聞在以下地區被揭露：
翻譯 Bunny
翻譯 Levi
翻譯 Mark
翻譯 夏洛
翻譯 苦瓜
一校 小P
總校 Peach
時軸 Bunny
特效 一隻蠢喵
壓制 hhjie
總監 Luke